the humans are still more powerful than
人类仍然比人工智能更强大。
the AIS the problem is that we are
问题在于我们
divided against each other and the
彼此分裂，
algorithms are using our weaknesses
算法正在利用我们的弱点来
against us and this is very dangerous
对付我们，这非常危险。
because once you believe that people who
一旦你认为与你
don't think like you are your enemies
想法不同的人是你的敌人，
democracy collapses and then the
民主就会崩溃，
election becomes like a war so if
选举就会变成一场战争。所以，如果
something ultimately destroys us it will
最终有什么摧毁了我们，那将
be our own delusions not the AIS we have
是我们自己的错觉，而不是人工智能。
a big election in the United States yes
美国即将举行大选，没错，
democracy in the states is quite fragile
美国的民主相当脆弱，
but the big problem is what if
但最大的问题是：如果……
surely that will never happen youal Noah
当然，这种情况永远不会发生。尤尔·诺亚·
Harari the author of some of the most
赫拉利，当今
influential non-fiction books in the
世界上最具影响力的非虚构类书籍的作者，
world today and is now at the Forefront
现在正站在
of exploring the worldshaping power of
探索
AI and how it is beyond anything
人工智能塑造世界的力量及其如何超越
Humanity has ever faced before biggest
人类以往所面临的一切的最前沿。
social networks in the world they're
世界上最大的社交网络
effectively going to go for free speech
实际上正在攻击言论自由，
what is your take on that the issue is
你对此有何看法？问题
not the humans the issue is the
不在于人类，而在于
algorithms so let me unpack this in the
算法。让我来解释一下。在
2010s there was a big battle between
2010年代，
algorithms for human attention now the
算法之间为了争夺人类的注意力而展开了一场激烈的斗争。
algorithms discovered when you look at
算法发现，回顾
history the easiest way to grab human
历史，抓住人类注意力的最简单方法
attention is to press the fear button
是按下恐惧按钮，按下
the hate button the greed button the
仇恨按钮。 贪婪按钮的
problem is that there was a misalignment
问题在于，算法
between the goal that was defined to the
设定的目标
algorithm and the interests of human
与人类社会的利益存在偏差。
society but this is how it becomes
但
really disconcerting because if so much
真正令人不安的是，如果仅仅因为
damage was done by giving the wrong goal
给
to A Primitive social media algorithm
一个原始的社交媒体算法设定了错误的目标就造成了如此巨大的破坏，那么
what would be the results with AI in 20
20或30年后人工智能又会带来怎样的后果呢？
or 30 years so what's the solution we've
那么解决方案是什么？历史上我们曾
been in this situation many times before
多次遇到这种情况，
in history and the answer is always the
答案总是
same which is are you optimistic I try
相同的：你乐观吗？我努力
to be a
保持
realist this is a sentence I never
现实主义。我这辈子都没
thought I'd say in my life um we've just
想过自己会说出这样的话。嗯，我们的
hit 7 million subscribers on YouTube and
YouTube频道刚刚突破了700万订阅用户，
I want to say a huge thank you to all of
我要衷心感谢
you that show up here every Monday and
每周一和
Thursday to watch our conversations um
周四都来观看我们节目的每一位观众。我不仅要代表
from the bottom of my heart but also on
我自己，还要代表
behalf of my team who you don't always
我的团队（你们不一定有机会
get to meet there's almost 50 people now
见到他们）向你们致谢。现在，在CEO的领导下，有近50位员工在为这个频道
behind the D of a CEO that work to put
付出努力。
this together so from all of us thank
所以，我们所有人都要向你们表示衷心的感谢。
you so much um we did a raffle last
嗯，我们上个月举办了一次抽奖活动，为
that subscribed to the show up until 7
订阅我们节目的观众送出了奖品。 直到我们拥有700万
million subscribers and you guys love
订阅用户，你们都非常喜欢这个
that raffle so much that we're going to
抽奖活动，所以我们决定
continue it so every single month we're
继续举办。每个月我们都会
giving away money can't buy prizes
送出千金难买的奖品，
including meetings with me invites to
包括与我见面、参加
our events and ,000 gift vouchers to
我们活动的邀请，以及价值1000美元的礼品券，
anyone that subscribes to the DI Co
所有订阅DI Co的用户都能获得。
there's now more than 7 million of you
现在我们已经有超过700万订阅用户了，
so if you make the decision to subscribe
所以如果你今天决定订阅，
today you can be one of those lucky
你就有机会成为这些幸运儿之一。衷心
people thank you from the bottom of my
感谢你们！
heart let's get to the conversation
让我们进入正题。
10 years ago you made a video that was
10年前，你制作了一个
titled why humans run the world it's a
名为“为什么人类主宰世界”的视频，这是你
very well-known Ted Talk that you
非常著名的TED演讲。
did after reading your new book Nexus I
读完你的新书《Nexus》后，我
wanted to ask you a slightly modified
想问你一个稍作修改的
question which is do you still believe
问题：你是否仍然相信
that 10 years from now humans will
10年后人类仍将从
fundamentally be running the
根本上主宰
world I'm not sure it depends on the
世界？我不确定，这取决于
decisions we all take in the coming
我们未来几年做出的决定，
years but there is a chance that the
但答案有可能是
answer is no that in 10 years um
否定的，10年后，
algorithms and AIS will be running the
算法和人工智能系统（AIS）可能会主宰
world I'm not having in mind some kind
世界。我指的不是
of hollywoodian Science Fiction scenario
好莱坞电影里那种科幻场景。 科幻小说
of one big computer kind of Conquering
里那种一台大型计算机征服
the world it's more like a bureaucracy
世界的场景，更像是
of AIS that we will have millions of AI
人工智能系统（AI）的官僚机构。我们会
bureaucrats everywhere um you know in
在
the banks in the government in
银行、政府、
businesses in universities making more
企业、大学等各个领域看到数百万的AI官僚，它们会越来越多地参与到
and more decisions about about our lives
我们生活的
that um everyday decisions whether to
决策中，比如是否
give us a loan whether to accept us to a
给我们贷款、是否录用我们等等。
job uh and we will find it more and more
我们会越来越
difficult to understand the logic the
难以理解这些决策背后的逻辑和
rationale why the algorithm refused to
理由，比如为什么算法拒绝
give us a loan why the algorithm
给我们贷款，为什么算法
accepted somebody else uh uh to for the
录用了其他人。当然，
job and um you know you could still have
我们仍然可以拥有
democracies with people voting for this
民主制度，人民投票选举
president or this prime minister but um
总统或总理，但
if most of the decisions are made by AIS
如果大部分决策都由AI做出，
and humans including the politicians
而包括政治家在内的人类
have difficulty understanding the reason
难以理解
why the AIS are making a particular
AI做出特定
decision then power will gradually shift
决策的原因，那么权力就会逐渐
from
从
Humanity uh to these new alien
人类转移到这些新的外星
intelligences alien intelligences yeah I
智能手中。是的，我更
prefer to think about AI I I know that
倾向于把AI理解为外星智能。我知道AI
the acronym is artificial intelligence
是人工智能的缩写，
but I think it's more accurate to think
但我认为更准确的说法是
about it as an alien int intelligence
外星智能，而
not in the sense of coming from out of
不是指来自
space in the sense that it makes
外太空的智能。 从某种意义上说，
way than than human mind artificial
人工智能的决策方式与人类思维截然不同，
means or or have the sense that we
或者说，它并非由人类
design it we control it some something
设计或控制，而是由人类
artificial is made by humans with each
制造的。随着
passing year AI is becoming less and
时间的推移，人工智能变得越来越不像人类，
less artificial and more and more alien
越来越像外星生物。
uh yes we still design the kind of baby
是的，我们仍然设计早期的
AIS but then they learn and they change
人工智能系统，但它们会学习、会改变，
and they start making uh unexpected
开始做出意想不到的
decisions and they start coming up with
决策，开始提出与
human way of of doing things you know
人类做事方式截然不同的新想法。你知道，
game of Go that in 2016 alpago defeated
围棋就有一个著名的例子。2016年，阿尔帕戈击败了
the world champion Lisa do but the
世界冠军丽莎·杜。但最令人
amazing thing about it was was the way
惊叹的是它获胜的方式。
it it did it because humans have been
人类
playing go for 20 500 years a board game
玩围棋已经有20500年的历史了。围棋是一种棋类游戏，
a board game a a strategy game developed
一种起源
in ancient China and considered one of
于古代中国的策略游戏，被认为是
civilized person in East in East Asia
东亚文明人必须
had to know and tens of millions of
掌握的基本技艺之一。数以千万计的
Chinese and Koreans and Japanese played
中国人、韩国人和日本人玩了几个
go for centuries entire philosophies
世纪的围棋，围绕着围棋的玩法发展出了完整的哲学体系。围棋被
it it was considered a good preparation
认为是
for politics and for life and people
为政治和人生做准备的良好途径。人们
thought that they explored the
认为…… 探索了围棋的
entire uh uh realm the entire geography
整个领域，整个地理
landscape of go and then alphago came
格局，然后AlphaGo出现了，它向
along and showed us that actually for
我们展示了，实际上，
2,500 years people were exploring just a
2500年来人们探索的只是围棋
landscape of go there are completely
格局中非常小的一部分。围棋的下法存在着完全
different strategies of how to play the
不同的策略，而
game that not a single human being came
人类在
up with in more than 2,000 years of
2000多年的
playing it and Alpha go came up with it
游戏历史中却从未想到过这些策略，AlphaGo却在
in just a few days so this is alien
短短几天内就做到了。所以，这就是外星
intelligence and you know if it's just a
智能。你知道，如果这只是一个
game then but the same thing is likely
游戏，那当然可以理解，但同样的事情也可能
to happen in finance in medicine in
发生在金融、医学、
religion For Better or For
宗教等领域。无论
Worse you wrote this book Nexus Nexus
好坏，你写了这本书，书名是《Nexus Nexus》，Nexus
how do you pronounce it Nexus Nexus I'm
Nexus怎么发音？我
not an expert on pronunciation
不是发音专家。
so you could have written
你本来可以写
many a book um you're someone that's I
很多书的，嗯，我
think broadly curious about the nature
认为你对
of life but also the nature of history
生命的本质以及历史的本质都非常好奇。
for you to write a book that is so
你写了一本如此
detailed and comprehensive there must
详尽全面的书，一定
have been a pretty strong reason why
有非常充分的理由，为什么
this book had to come from you now and
这本书必须出自你之手。
why is that because I think we need a
为什么呢？因为我认为我们需要一个关于
historical perspective on on the AI
人工智能的历史视角。
Revolution I mean there are many books
革命，我的意思是，关于人工智能的书有很多，但《
about about AI this is Nexus is not a
Nexus》这
book about the about AI it's a book
本书并不是关于人工智能的，而是
about the long-term history of
关于
information networks I think that to
信息网络长期发展史的。我认为，要
understand what is really new and
理解人工智能真正的新颖之处和
important about AI we need perspective
重要意义，我们需要回顾
of thousands of years to go back and
数千年的历史，
look at previous information revolutions
看看之前的信息革命，
like the invention of writing and the
比如文字、
printing press and the radio and only
印刷机和无线电的发明。只有
then you really start to understand what
这样，你才能真正开始理解
is happening around us right now uh one
我们现在周围正在发生的事情。
thing you understand for instance is
例如，你要明白的一点是，
that AI is really different people
人工智能确实与众不同。人们把
compare it to previous revolutions but
它与之前的革命进行比较，但它的
it it's different because it's the first
不同之处在于，它是人类
technology ever in human history that is
历史上第一种
able to make decisions
能够
independently and to create new ideas
独立决策和独立创造新想法的技术。
independently a printing press could
印刷机可以
print my book but it could not write it
印刷我的书，但它不能写，它只能
it could just copy my ideas an atom bomb
复制我的想法。原子弹
could destroy a city but it could it
可以摧毁一座城市，但它不能自己
can't decide by itself which City to bom
决定炸哪座城市，也不能自己决定
or why to Bone it and AI can do that and
为什么要炸。而人工智能可以做到这一点。
you know there is a lot of hype right
你知道，
now around AI so people get confused
现在人工智能被炒作得沸沸扬扬，人们很容易感到困惑，
because they now try to sell us to sell
因为他们现在试图把
us everything as AI like you want to
所有东西都包装成人工智能来推销。比如你想把
sell this table to somebody oh it's it's
这张桌子卖给别人，哦，它…… 这
an it's an AI table and this water this
是一张人工智能桌子，这水也是
is AI water so people what is AI
人工智能水。所以，大家，什么是人工智能？
everything is AI no not everything um
所有东西都是人工智能吗？不，并非所有东西都是。嗯，
there is a lot of automation out there
现在有很多自动化设备，但它们
which is not AI if you think about a
并非人工智能。想想看，一台
coffee machine that makes coffee for you
咖啡机可以为你制作咖啡，它会
it does things automatically but it's
自动完成一些操作，但它
not an AI it's pre-programmed by humans
不是人工智能。它是人类预先编程的，只能
to do certain things and it can never
执行某些操作，它永远无法自主
learn or change by
学习或改变。
itself a coffee machine becomes an AI if
只有当
you come to the coffee machine in the
你早上来到咖啡机前
morning and the Machine tells hey based
，机器告诉你：“嘿，
on what I know about you I guess that
根据我对你的了解，我猜
you would like an
你会喜欢一杯
espresso it learned something about you
浓缩咖啡。”它才算是人工智能。它了解了你的一些信息，然后
independent decision it doesn't wait for
独立做出决定，无需
you to ask for the espresso and it's
你开口。
it's really AI if it tells you and and I
如果它告诉你：“我
just came up with a new drink it's
刚刚研发了一种新饮品，
called Buffy and I think you would like
叫做‘巴菲’，我想你会喜欢的。”这才是
it that's really AI when it comes up
真正的人工智能。当它提出
with completely new ideas that we did
我们没有
anticipate and this is a GameChanger in
预先编程、也没有预料到的全新想法时，这才是真正的人工智能。这在
history it's it's bigger than the
历史上具有颠覆性意义，它比印刷机更伟大。
bomb you said we need to have a
你说我们需要从
historical perspective and do you
历史的角度看待问题，这比原子弹还要重要。你
consider yourself to be a historian yes
认为自己是历史学家吗？是的，我的
that that's my my profession is a
职业是
historian that that's kind of this is my
历史学家，这是我的
training I was originally a specialist
专业。我最初是
in medieval military history I wrote
中世纪军事史专家，我写过
about the H Crusades and the 100 Years
关于十字军东征、百年
War and the strategy and lo Logistics of
战争以及14世纪入侵法国的英军战略和后勤的文章。
in the 14th century this was my my first
这些是我的第一批
articles um and this is the kind of of
文章。嗯，
perspective or of knowledge that I also
我也运用这种视角和知识来
bring to try and understand what's
尝试理解
happening now with with AI because most
人工智能的现状。因为大多数
people's understanding of what AI is
人对人工智能的理解都
comes from them playing around with a
来自于他们摆弄
large language model like chat PT or
大型语言模型，比如ChatPT、
gemini or Gro or something that's like
Gemini或Gro之类的。
their understanding of it you can ask it
他们的理解是，你可以问它
a question and it gives you an answer
一个问题，它会给你一个答案。这就是
that's really what people think of AI as
人们对人工智能的普遍看法。
and so it's easy to be a bit complacent
因此，人们很容易
with it or to see this technological
对此感到沾沾自喜，或者认为这种技术
shift as being
变革
trivial but when you start talking about
微不足道。但是，当你开始谈论
information
信息，谈论
information and information networks and
信息流和信息网络的中断，以及
when you bring it back through history
你重新审视人工智能时，你会发现它远比你想象的复杂。 历史，
and and you give us this perspective on
以及你从
the fact that information effectively
信息有效
glues us all together then it starts to
维系我们所有人的角度出发，让我开始从
completely differently I mean there are
完全不同的角度思考这个问题。我的意思是，我有
two ways I think about it I mean one way
两种思考方式。一种方式是，
is that when you realize that as you
正如你所说，当你意识到
said that information is is the basis
信息是
for everything when you start to shake
一切的基础时，一旦动摇了
the basis everything can collapse or or
基础，一切都可能崩溃、
change or or something new could come up
改变，或者出现新的事物。
for instance uh um democracies are made
例如，民主制度的实现
possible only by Information Technology
离不开信息技术。
democracy in essence is a conversation a
民主本质上是一种对话，
group of people conversing talking
一群人交谈、讨论，
trying to make decisions together
试图共同做出决定。
dictatorship is a somebody dictates
独裁则是某人独断专行，
everything one person dictates
一个人独断专行。这就是独裁。民主是一种对话。
is a conversation now in the Stone Age
在石器时代，
hunter gatherers living in small bands
生活在小群体中的狩猎采集者
they were mostly Democratic whenever the
大多实行民主制度。每当群体
band need to decide anything they could
需要做出决定时，他们都可以互相
just talk with each other and and decide
交谈并做出决定。
as human societies grew bigger it just
随着人类社会规模的扩大，
became technically difficult to hold the
进行对话在技术上变得越来越困难。
conversation so the only examples we
因此，我们
have from the ancient world for
从古代世界找到的
democracies are small city states like
民主例子只有像
Athens or republican Rome these are the
雅典或罗马共和国这样的小城邦。这是
two most famous examples not the only
两个最著名的例子，并非仅有的例子，
ones but the most famous and even the
但却是最著名的。即使在
Ancients even philosophers like Plato
古代，民主制度也并非完全由个人主导。 像柏拉图
and Aristotle they knew once you go
和亚里士多德这样的哲学家早就知道，一旦
beyond the level of a citystate
超越城邦的层面，
democracy is impossible we do not know
民主就不可能存在。我们找不到
of a single example from the premodern
任何前现代
world of a large scale democracy
世界大规模民主的例子，
millions of people spread over a large
数百万人口分散在广袤的
territory conducting their political
领土上，以民主的方式处理政治
Affairs
事务。
democratically why not because of this
这并非因为某个
or that dictator that took power because
独裁者掌权，而是因为
democracy was simply impossible you
民主在当时根本不可能实现。如果
millions of people when you don't have
没有
the right
合适的
technology de large scale democracy
技术，数百万人之间根本无法进行对话。大规模民主
becomes Possible only in the late modern
只有在近代晚期才成为可能，
era when a couple of information
当时一些信息
Technologies appear first the newspaper
技术出现，先是报纸，
then Telegraph and radio and and
然后是电报、广播和
television and they make large scale
电视，它们使大规模
democracy possible so democracy it's not
民主成为可能。所以，民主并非是
you have these information Technologies
信息技术之外的产物。
now the basis of democracy is
如今，信息技术是民主的基础。
information technology so if you have
因此，如果信息技术领域发生
some kind of Earth quake in the
某种“地震”，
information technology like the rise of
例如
social media or the rise of AI this is
社交媒体或人工智能的兴起，必然会
bound to shake democracy which is now
动摇民主。而
what we see around the world is that we
我们现在看到的正是这样的情况：我们
have the most sophisticated information
拥有历史上最先进的信息
technology in history and people can't
技术，但人们却无法
talk with each other the Democratic
彼此交流。民主
conversation is breaking down and every
对话正在瓦解，每个
country has its own explanation like you
国家都有自己的解释，比如你
talk to Americans what's happening there
和美国人交谈时就会发现这一点。
between Democrats and Republicans why
民主党和共和党之间到底发生了什么？为什么
can't they agree on even the most basic
他们连最基本的
facts and they give you all these
事实都无法达成一致？他们总是用
of American history and Society but you
美国历史和社会的特殊性来解释，但你
see the same thing in Brazil you see the
在巴西、法国、菲律宾也看到了同样的情况。
Philippines so it can't be the unique
所以，问题不可能出在某个
conditions of this or that country it's
国家的特殊性上，而是
the underlying technological Revolution
根本的技术革命。
um that I I bring from history is how
我从历史中学到的另一点是，即使是
even relatively small technological
相对较小的技术
changes or seemingly small changes
变革，或者看似微小的变革，
can have far-reaching
也会产生深远的
consequences like you think about the
影响。想想
invention of writing originally it was
文字的发明，
mud I mean writing was invented for the
最初人们只是在泥土上玩耍。文字的发明并非一蹴而就，
places but the most the first time in
而是在
ancient Mesopotamia people take clay
古代美索不达米亚。人们用泥板（
tablets which is basically pieces of mud
其实就是泥块）
and they take a stick and they use the
和
stick to make marks in the in the clay
棍子在泥板上刻字，
in the clay in the in the mud and this
这
is the invention of writing and this had
就是文字的发明。它产生了
a profound effect to give just one
深远的影响。举个
example um you think about ownership
例子，想想所有权。
what does it mean to own something like
拥有某物意味着什么？比如
I own a house I own a field so
我拥有一栋房子，我拥有一块田地。在
previously before writing to own a field
文字出现之前，拥有一块田地…… 假设
if you live in a small Mesopotamian
你生活在
Village like 7,000 years ago you own a
7000年前美索不达米亚的一个小村庄，你拥有一块
field this is a community Affair it
田地。这属于社区事务，
means that your neighbors agree that
意味着你的邻居们都同意
this field is yours and they don't pick
这块田地是你的，他们不会在
fruits there and they don't graze their
那里采摘水果，也不会在那里放牧
sheep there because they agree it's
羊群，因为他们都认同这块田地是
yours it's a community agreement then
你的。这是社区协议。后来
comes writing and you have written
文字出现了，有了书面
documents and ownership changes its
文件，所有权的
meaning now to own a field or a house
含义也随之改变。现在，拥有一块田地或一栋房子
means that there is some piece of dry
意味着
mud somewhere in the archive of the king
国王的档案馆里某处保存着一块干泥，上面有
with marks on it that says that you own
标记，表明你拥有
that field
这块田地或房子。
so suddenly ownership is not a matter of
突然之间，所有权不再是
neighbors it's a matter of which
邻居之间的社区协议，而是取决于
document sits in the archive of the king
国王档案馆里保存着哪份文件。
and it also means for instance that you
这也意味着，例如，你
can sell your land to a stranger without
可以把土地卖给陌生人，而无需征得
the permission of your neighbors simply
邻居的同意，只需把
by giving the stranger this piece of dry
这块干
mud in exchange for gold or silver or
泥交给陌生人，换取金银或
whatever so what a big change a
其他物品即可。多么巨大的变化啊！一个
seemingly simple invention like using a
看似简单的发明，比如用一根
stick to to draw some some signs on a
棍子在泥地上画几个标记，就能带来如此巨大的改变。
piece of mud and and now think about
现在想想
what AI will do to ownership like maybe
人工智能会如何影响所有权，比如
10 years down the line to own your house
10年后，拥有你的房子
means that some AI says that you own it
意味着…… 人工智能说你拥有它，
and if the AI suddenly says that you
但如果人工智能突然说你
don't own it for whatever reason that
不拥有它，不管出于什么
you don't even know that's it it's not
你甚至不知道的原因，那就是它不属于
yours that that Mark on that piece of
你了。
mud was also the invention of sort of
泥地上的那个印记也是某种
written language
书面语言的发明。
and I think I was thinking about when I
我在
was reading your book about how language
读你的书时一直在想，语言是如何
holds our society together not in the
维系我们社会的，不是
way that we we often might assume as in
我们通常认为的那种方式，比如
me having a conversation with you but
我和你交谈，而是
passwords um poet passwords uh like
密码，嗯，诗人的密码，比如
banking it's like our whole society is
银行账户，就像我们整个社会都由
secured by language yeah and the first
语言保障一样。是的，
thing that the AIS have mastered is with
人工智能掌握的第一项技能就是
large language models is the ability to
大型语言模型的
replicate that which is which made me I
复制能力，这让我
think about all the things that in my
想到我生活中所有由
language even my relationships now
语言维系的事物，甚至包括我的人际关系，
because I don't see my friends my
因为我见不到我的朋友，他们
friends live in Dubai and America and
住在迪拜、美国和
Mexico so we conversate in language our
墨西哥，所以我们用语言交流，我们
our relationships are held together in
的关系也由
language and as you said democracies are
语言维系。正如你所说，民主制度也由
held together in language um and now
语言维系。现在，
there's a more intelligent Force that's
有一种更智能的力量
mastered that yeah it was so unexpected
掌握了语言，是的，这太出乎意料了。
like you know five years ago people said
你知道，五年前人们说
AI will Master this or that self-driving
人工智能会掌握这个或那个。 自动驾驶
vehicles but language nah this is such a
汽车，但语言，嗯，这真是个
complicated problem this is a the human
复杂的问题。语言是人类的
Masterpiece language it will never
杰作，它永远无法被人类完全
Master language and CH GPT came and it
掌握。而GPT出现了，
is you know I'm I'm a words person and
你知道，我是个文字爱好者，
I'm simply Amazed by the quality of the
我简直被
texts that uh these large language
这些大型
language models produce it's not perfect
语言模型生成的文本质量惊艳到了。它们并不完美，
but uh they really understand the
但它们确实理解了
semantic field of words they can string
词语的语义场，能够将
words together and sentences to form a
词语和句子串联起来，形成
coherent text that that's really
连贯的文本，这真的很
remarkable and as you said I mean this
了不起。正如你所说，这
is the basis for everything like I give
是一切的基础。比如，我用
instructions to my bank with language if
语言向银行下达指令。如果
AI can generate text and audio and image
人工智能可以生成文本、音频和图像，
then how do I communicate with the bank
那么我该如何与银行沟通，才能避免被
manipulation by an AI but the tempting
人工智能操纵呢？
part in that sentence is you don't like
这句话的诱人之处在于，你本来就不喜欢
communicating with your bank anyway as
和银行沟通，比如
in calling them being on the phone
打电话，然后一直
waiting for another human so the temp
等着接听。所以，
the Temptation is know I don't like
诱惑在于，既然我不喜欢
speaking to my bank anyway so I'm
和银行说话，那就
goingon to let the AI do that I'm gonna
让人工智能来做吧。
invest if I can trust them I mean the
如果我能信任它们，我就会投资。我的意思是，
big question is I mean why does the bank
最大的问题是，银行为什么要这么做？ 你
want me to call personally to make sure
想让我亲自打电话确认
that it's really me it's not somebody
真的是我，而不是其他人
else telling the bank oh make this
告诉银行“哦，把这笔钱
transfer to to I don't know Cayman
转到……我不知道，开曼
Islands it's really me and how do you
群岛”，真的是我吗？你怎么
make sure how do you build this is TR I
确保？你怎么构建这个？我的
mean the the Hall of Finance for
意思是，
thousands of years is just one question
几千年来金融界的核心只有一个问题：
trust all these Financial devices money
信任。所有这些金融工具，金钱
itself is really just trust it's not
本身，实际上就是信任。它不是
made from gold or silver or paper or
用黄金、白银、纸张或
anything it's how do you create trust
其他任何东西制成的，而是如何在
between strangers and therefore most
陌生人之间建立信任。因此，大多数
Financial inventions in the end they are
金融发明最终都是
linguistic and symbolic inventions it's
语言和符号的发明，
not you don't need some complicated
不需要复杂的
physics it's it's complicated symbolism
物理学，只需要复杂的符号学。
and now AI might start creating new
现在，人工智能可能会开始创造新的
Financial devices and and will Master
金融工具，并掌握
Finance because it mastered language and
金融，因为它掌握了语言。
and like you said I mean we now
就像你说的，我们现在可以
communicate with other people our
和
friends all over the world you know in
世界各地的朋友交流。你知道，在
the 2010s there was a big battle between
2010年代，
algorithms for human attention we're
算法之间为了争夺人类的注意力展开了一场激烈的竞争。我们在
just discussing it before the podcast
播客之前讨论过这个问题，
like how do we get the attention of
比如我们如何才能吸引人们的注意力。
people but there is something even more
但是，还有比注意力更强大的东西，
that's intimacy
那就是亲密关系。
if you really want to influence people
真正想影响人们的是
intimacy is is more powerful than
亲密感，它比关注更有力量。
attention how are you defining Intimacy
你如何定义亲密感？
in this regard someone that you have a
就此而言，亲密感是指你
long-term acquaintance with that you
长期认识、了解、
know personally that you trust that to
信任、在
some extent that you love that you care
某种程度上爱着、关心的人。
about um and until today it was utterly
嗯，直到今天，伪装亲密感是完全
impossible to fake
不可能的，
intimacy and to must produce intimacy
而制造亲密感则不然。
you know dictators could must produce
你知道，独裁者可以制造
attention you know once you have for
关注。比如，一旦有了
instance radio you can tell all the
广播，你就可以告诉
people in Nazi Germany or in the Soviet
纳粹德国或苏联的所有人，
Union the great leader is giving a
伟大的领袖正在发表
speech everybody must turn their radio
讲话，每个人都必须打开收音机
on and listen so you can Mass produce
收听，这样你就可以大规模地制造
attention but this is not intimacy you
关注。但这并非亲密感，你
don't have intimacy with the great
无法与伟大的领袖建立亲密关系。
leader now with AI you can for the first
现在有了人工智能，历史上第一次，至少在理论上，你可以
must produce intimacy with millions of
与数百万可能为政府工作的人制造亲密关系，这些人正在
relationships with us which will be hard
与我们建立虚假的亲密关系，而我们很难
to to know that this is a bot and not a
分辨这是机器人而不是真人。
being H it's interesting because when I
这很有意思，因为
I've had so many conversations with
我与许多
relationship experts and a variety of
关系专家和各界
people that speak to the decline
人士进行过对话，他们都谈到了
in human to human intimacy and the rise
人与人之间亲密感的下降和人工智能的兴起。
in loneliness and us becoming more um
孤独感加剧，社会变得越来越
sexless as a society and all of these
无性，诸如此类的
kinds of things so it's it's almost with
事情，几乎都与
the decline in human to human intimacy
人与人之间亲密关系
and human- to human connection and the
和人与人之间联系的衰落有关。 随着
rise of the sort of AR the possibility
增强现实（AR）等技术的兴起，以及
of artificial intimacy it begs the
人工智能可能带来的亲密感，
question what the future might look like
未来会是什么样子？
in a world where people are lonlier than
人们比
ever more disconnected than ever but
以往任何时候都更加孤独、更加疏离，却
still have the same maslovian need for
仍然有着同样的马斯洛需求层次理论——对
that connection and that feeling of you
联结、对
know love and belonging and maybe this
爱和归属感的渴求。或许这就是
is why we're seeing a rise in
为什么我们
polarization at the same time because
同时看到社会两极分化加剧的原因，因为
people are desperately trying to belong
人们迫切地想要找到归属感，
somewhere and the algorithm is like
而算法就像是在
reinforcing my echo chamber so you know
强化我的回音室效应。
it's but I don't know how that
但我不知道最终结果会如何，
ends I don't think it's deterministic it
我认为这并非必然，它
depends on the decision we make
取决于我们
individually and as a society uh there
个人和社会的选择。
are of course also wonderful things that
当然，
this technology can do for us uh the
这项技术也能为我们带来许多美好的事物，例如
ability of AI to hold a conversation the
人工智能能够进行对话，
ability to understand your emotions it
能够理解你的情绪。这
can potentially mean that we will have
可能意味着我们将拥有
lots of AI teachers and AI uh uh doctors
大量的人工智能教师、人工智能医生
and AI therapists that can give us
和人工智能治疗师，他们可以为我们提供
Education Services than ever before
前所未有的优质医疗保健和教育服务，而不是像现在这样，在
class of 40 other kids that the teacher
40个孩子组成的班级里，老师
is barely able to give attention to this
几乎无法顾及到每个孩子。 如果
particular child and understand his or
能了解这个孩子的
her specific needs and his or her
具体需求和
specific personality you can have an A
个性，你就可以拥有一个
AI tutor that is focused entirely on you
完全专注于你的AI导师，为
and that is able to give you a quality
你提供
of Education which is really
真正
unparalleled I had this debate with my
无与伦比的优质教育。我
friend uh on the weekend he's got two
周末和朋友讨论过这个问题，他有两个
young kids who are one years old and
孩子，一个一岁，一个
three years old and we were discussing
三岁。我们讨论了
in the future in sort of 16 years time
未来，大概16年后，
where would you rather send your child
你会把孩子送到哪里？是像
you've described with lots of people
你描述的那样，在教室里由人类老师授课，人
lots of noise where they're not getting
多嘈杂，无法获得
personalized learning so if the
个性化学习，如果
classroom are more intelligent they're
教室里的学生更聪明，他们就会被
being left behind if they're more
落下，
or would you rather your child sat in
或者被拖后腿；还是你会让孩子坐在
front of a screen potentially or a
屏幕前，或者坐在
humanoid robot and was given really
人形机器人前，接受真正
personalized tailored
个性化的定制
education that was probably
教育？这种教育可能
significantly cheaper than say private
比私立
education or
教育或
university but you need the combination
大学教育便宜得多，但你需要两者结合。
I mean I think that the the for for many
我的意思是，我认为对于很多
of the lessons
课程来说，
it will be better to go with the AI
AI导师会更好，
tutor which again you don't even have to
而且你甚至不必
sit in in in front of a screen you can
坐在屏幕前，你可以……
go to the park and get a a lesson on on
把车停好，
on ecology just listening on on on as as
边走边听，
you walk but you will need uh large
就能学到一堂生态课。不过，课间休息时需要一
groups of kids for break time because
大群孩子，因为
very often you learn the the most
很多时候，
important lessons in school are not
学校里最重要的知识不是在课堂上学到的，而是在
learned during the lessons they are
课间
learned during the breaks and this is
休息时学到的。这
something that should not be automated
不应该自动化，所以
uh you would still need large group of
仍然需要一大群
of children together with with human
孩子，并且需要有人
supervision uh for that the other thing
监督。
I I thought about a lot when I was
我在
reading your book is this idea that I
读你的书时一直在思考另一个问题：我原以为
would assume that us having more
我们拥有更多
information and more access to
信息和更多获取
information would lead to more truth in
信息的途径，会让世界变得更加真实，
the world less conspiracy more agreement
阴谋论减少，共识增多。
but that doesn't seem to be the case no
但事实并非如此，完全不是。
not at all uh most information in the
世界上大部分信息
world is junk I mean I think the best
都是垃圾。我的意思是，我认为最好的
way to think about it is it's it's like
理解方式是，就像
food that there was a time like a
食物一样。大约一个
century ago in many countries where food
世纪前，许多国家食物
was scarce so people ate whatever they
匮乏，人们什么都吃，
could get especially it was full of fat
尤其是那些富含脂肪
and sugar uh and they thought that more
和糖的食物。他们认为
food is always good like if you ask your
食物越多越好。如果你问你的
great grandmother she would yes more
曾祖母，她肯定会说，
food is always good and then we reach a
食物越多越好。然后我们……
time of abundance in in in food and uh
食物曾经非常丰富，
we have all these
我们现在拥有大量
industrialized processed food which is
工业加工食品，这些食品人为
artificially full of fat and sugar and
地添加了大量的脂肪、糖、盐
salt and whatever and it's obviously ban
等等。显然，认为
for us the idea that more food is always
食物越多越好的想法对我们来说是错误的，尤其是那些
junk food and the same thing has
垃圾食品。
happened with information that
信息也经历了同样的过程。过去
information was once scarce so if you
信息匮乏，如果你
could get your hands on a book you would
能找到一本书，你就会
read it because it was nothing else and
读它，因为它是无价之宝。而
now information is abundant we are
现在信息爆炸，我们被
flooded by information and much f is
信息淹没，其中很多都是
junk information which is artificially
垃圾信息，充斥着
full of greed and anger and fear because
贪婪、愤怒和恐惧，都是因为人们在
of this battle for
争夺
attention um and it's not good for us so
注意力。这对我们有害。所以
we basically need to go on an
我们基本上需要进行
information diet that uh again the first
信息节食。首先，我们要
step is to realize that it's not the
意识到
case that more information is always
信息并非越多越好，
good for us we need a limited amount and
我们需要适量，而且
we actually need more time to
我们需要更多的时间来
digest the information and we have to be
消化信息。
off of course also careful about the
当然，我们也要注意信息
quality of what we take in because uh
的质量，因为
again of the abundance of of junk
垃圾信息泛滥。
misconception I think is this link
我认为人们普遍存在一个误解，那就是
between information and truth that
信息与真理之间存在联系。
people think okay if I get a lot of
他们认为，如果我获得大量信息，就意味着我掌握了真理。
information this is the raw material of
信息是
Truth and I more information will mean
真理的原材料，我以为信息越多就意味着
knowledge and that's not the case
知识越多，但事实并非如此。
because even in nature most information
即使在自然界，大多数信息也
is not about the truth the basic
并非关于真理。
function of information in history and
信息在历史和生物学中的基本功能
also in biology is to connect
是连接。
information is
信息即
connection and when you look at history
连接。纵观历史，
you see that very often the easiest way
你会发现，连接人们最简单的方法往往
to connect people is not with the truth
不是用真理，
because the truth is a is a costly and
因为真理是一种昂贵
and and rare kind of information it's
且稀缺的信息。
usually easier to connect people with
通常，用幻想和虚构来连接人们更容易。
fantasy with fiction uh why because the
为什么呢？因为真理
truth tends to be not just costly the
不仅昂贵，
truth tends to be complicated and it
而且往往复杂，
tends to be uncomfortable and sometimes
令人不适，有时甚至
painful if you think of you know like in
痛苦。想想
politics uh a politician who would tell
政治，一个愿意告诉
people the whole truth about their
人们国家全部真相的政治家
nation is unlikely to win the elections
不太可能赢得选举，
because every nation has these skeletons
因为每个国家都有
in the cuper and all these dark sides
不可告人的秘密，都有
and dark episodes that people don't want
人们不愿面对的阴暗面和黑暗历史。
with so we see that politically it's not
所以我们看到，在政治上，
uh uh if you want to connect Nations
如果你想连接国家、
religions political parties you often do
宗教和政党，你通常会
it with fictions and Fantasies and
用虚构、幻想和
fear um I was thinking about sapiens and
恐惧。我想到的是《智人》……
the role that stories play um in
故事在
engaging our brains and I was thinking a
调动我们大脑方面扮演着重要角色。我一直在思考
lot about the narratives in the UK we
英国的各种
have a narrative where we we're told
叙事方式。我们被告知，
we have in society are employment um
社会问题的根源很大程度上在于就业，而
other issues with crime are because
犯罪问题则是因为
there's people crossing from France on
有人从法国乘船偷渡。这种
effective narrative to get people to
叙事方式非常有效，能够促使人们
band together to march in the streets
团结起来走上街头游行。
and in America obviously the same
在美国，显然也有类似的
Narrative of the wall and the southern
叙事，比如边境墙和南部
border um they're crossing our border in
边境。人们被告知，
the millions it's their rapists it's
数百万人越过我们的边境，都是强奸犯，
then they're not sending their good
他们送来的不是好人，而是
institutions has galvanized people
精神病院的病人。这种叙事方式激起了人们的团结，他们
together and those people are now like
现在走上
marching in the streets and voting based
街头游行，并
on that story that is a fearful story
根据这种叙事方式进行投票。这是一个令人恐惧的故事，
it's a very powerful story because it
它非常有力，因为它
connects to something very deep in
触及了我们内心深处的某些东西。
inside us uh and if you want to get
如果你想吸引人们的
people's attention if you want to get
注意力，如果你想让
people's engagement so the fear button
人们参与进来，恐惧按钮
is one of the most efficient most
是人类大脑中最有效、最
effective buttons to press in the human
便捷的按钮之一，这种机制可以
mind and again goes back to the Stone
追溯到
Age so if you live in a stone age tribe
石器时代。所以，如果你生活在一个充满恐惧的世界里，恐惧就是最好的工具之一。 在石器时代部落里，
uh one of your biggest worries is that
你最大的担忧之一就是
the people from the other tribe will
其他部落的人会
come to your territory
闯入你的领地，
and you will take your food or we will
抢走你的食物，或者
kill you um so this is a very ingrained
杀了你。这种
fear in not just in humans in every
恐惧根深蒂固，不仅存在于人类，也存在于所有
Social Animal you they did experiments
社会性动物中。研究人员
on chimpanzees that show that
对黑猩猩进行过实验，结果表明
chimpanzees have a also a kind of almost
黑猩猩对
foreign chimpanzees from a different
来自其他部落的黑猩猩
band and politicians and religious
、政客和宗教
leaders and and and they learn how to
领袖也有一种近乎本能的恐惧或厌恶。他们学会了如何
play on these uh uh human emotions
利用人类的这些情绪，就像
almost like you play on a piano you know
弹钢琴一样。你知道，
originally these feelings like
最初，这些感觉（比如恐惧）的
discussed they evolved in order to help
进化是为了帮助
us um you know on the most basic level
我们。最基本的恐惧机制是，
especially as a kid you want to
尤其是在孩童时期，我们想要
experiment with different foods but if
尝试不同的食物，但如果你
you eat something that is bad for you
吃了对你有害的东西，
you need to to to you know puke it you
你
need to to to throw it out so you have
需要把它吐出来，扔掉。所以恐惧
discuss protecting you but then you have
保护着我们。然而，
throughout history hijacking this
历史上一些宗教和政治领袖却利用了这种
defensive mechanism and teaching people
防御机制，从小就教导人们
from a very young age to not just to
不仅要
fear but to be
恐惧，还要
disgusted by foreign people by people
厌恶。 外国人，尤其是那些
who look different and this is again you
长相不同的人，这再次表明，
as an adult you can learn all the
作为成年人，你可以学习各种
theories and you can educate yourself
理论，可以自我教育，明白
that this is not true but still very
这不是真的，但
deep in your mind if that there is a a
你内心深处仍然可能存在这样一种想法：这些
part that is just these people are
人
disgusting these people are
令人作呕，这些人很
dangerous and uh we saw it throughout
危险。纵观历史，我们看到
how many different movements have
许多不同的运动都
learned how to use this uh uh emotional
学会了如何利用这种情感
mechanisms to to motivate people we we
机制来激励人们。我们现在正处于
we sit down at a very interesting time
一个非常有趣的时期，
youal because two quite significant
因为
things have happened in the last I think
在过去
year as it relates to information and
一年里，发生了两件与信息和
many of the things we've been talking
我们一直在讨论的许多事情相关的重大事件。其中
about one of them is Elon Musk bought
一件是埃隆·马斯克收购了
Twitter and his real mandate has been
推特，他真正的使命是捍卫
this idea of free speech and as part of
言论自由。作为
that mandate he's unblocked a number of
这一使命的一部分，他解除了许多
figures who were previously blocked on
之前在推特上被封禁的人物的封禁，其中
Twitter um a lot of them right leaning
很多是右翼
people that were blocked for a variety
人士，他们被封禁的
of different reasons and then also this
原因各不相同。此外，本周
week Mark Zuckerberg released basically
马克·扎克伯格公开了
a letter publicly and in that letter he
一封信，他在信中
says that he
表示，他
re regrets the fact that he cooperated
后悔当初
so much with the FBI the government when
与联邦调查局和政府合作，
they asked him to censor things on
要求他审查内容。 在
Facebook one particular story he says he
Facebook上，他发了一个特别的故事，说他
regrets doing that and it looks like if
后悔这么做了。如果
you read between what he's saying well
你仔细品读他的话，你会发现
he actually says it explicitly he says
他其实明确地表示，
future if governments or anybody else
如果政府或其他任何人
asks us to censor certain messaging now
要求我们审查某些信息，我们将来会采取更强硬的反击。现在
what what I'm seeing is that Twitter
我看到的是，Twitter——
networks in the world and meta the
世界上最大的社交网络之一——以及Meta——
biggest social network in the world have
世界上最大的社交网络——
now taken this dance that effectively
现在采取了这种策略，实际上是在
they're going to let information flow
放任信息自由流动，
they're effectively going to go for this
实际上是在推行
free speech narrative now as someone
言论自由的叙事。作为一个
that's used these platforms for a long
长期使用这些平台（
time specifically X or Twitter it is
特别是Twitter）的人，我惊讶地发现
crazy how different it is these days
如今的情况变化如此之大。
there are things that I see every time I
我每次
scroll that I never would have seen
浏览网页都会看到一些以前从未见过的内容，这都与
before this free speech um position now
现在的言论自由立场有关。
I'm not taking a stance whether it's
我并不是要评判这种做法的
good or bad it's just very interesting
好坏，只是觉得它非常有趣。
and there's clearly an algorithm that is
显然，
now really like if I scroll if I go on X
现在的算法非常强大，比如，如果我现在浏览网页，
killed with a knife I reckon within 30
我估计30秒内就会看到有人被刀杀，或者
seconds and I will see someone getting
有人被
hit by a car um I will see extreme
车撞，我会看到各种极端事件。
islamophobia potentially um but then
伊斯兰恐惧症可能……嗯，但
I'll also see the other side so it's not
我也会看到另一面，所以
just I'm saying I'll see all of the
我并不是说我会看到所有
sides and when you talking earlier about
方面。你之前说的“这对
like is that good for me I I had a
我有好处吗？”我突然想起
flashback to my friend this weekend it
这个周末我朋友的情景。那天
was my birthday so my me and my friends
是我的生日，我和朋友们聚
were together just looking over at him
在一起，我看着他
videos on Twitter as he was sat on my
坐在我左边，漫不经心地在推特上刷恐怖视频，
left thinking God he's like frying his
心想天哪，他这是在刺激
dopamine receptors and I just I just
多巴胺受体吗？我只是
think this whole new like free speech
想说，现在这种所谓的言论自由
movement what is your take on this idea
运动，你对这种言论自由的看法是什么？
of free speech in the role you know only
你知道，只有
humans have free speech Bots don't have
人类才有言论自由，机器人没有。
free speech the tech companies are
科技公司
constantly confusing us about this issue
一直在这个问题上混淆视听，
because the issue is not the humans the
因为问题不在于人类，而在于
issue is the algorithms and let let me
算法。让我
explain what I mean if the question is
解释一下我的意思。如果问题是是否应该
whether to ban some somebody like Donald
禁止像唐纳德·
Trump from Twitter I agree this is a
特朗普这样的人在推特上发帖，我同意这是一个
very difficult issue and we should be
非常棘手的问题，我们应该
extremely careful about banning human
极其谨慎地对待禁止任何
beings especially important politicians
人，尤其是重要的政治人物，
from voicing their views and opinions
发表他们的观点和意见。
however much we dislike their opinions
无论我们多么不喜欢他们的观点
or or them personally it's a very
或他们本人，这都是一个非常严肃的问题。
serious matter to ban any human being
禁止任何人
from from a platform but this is not the
访问平台固然重要，但这并非
problem the problem on the platform is
问题的症结所在。平台的问题
not the human users the problem is the
不在于用户，而在于
algor ithms and the companies constantly
算法。公司
shift the blame to the humans in order
为了维护自身商业利益，不断将责任推卸给用户。
let let me unpack this humans create a
让我来分析一下：用户一直在创造
lot of content all the time they create
大量内容，包括
hateful content they create ceremon on
仇恨内容、宣扬同情的内容、
compassion they create cooking lessons
烹饪教程、
biology lessons so many different things
生物教程等等，
a flood of information the big question
信息爆炸。那么，关键问题
is then what gets human attention
在于：什么才能吸引用户的注意力？
everybody wants attention now
每个人都渴望关注。
uh the companies also want attention the
公司也同样渴望关注。
companies give the algorithms that run
公司给运行
the social media platforms a very simple
社交媒体平台的算法设定了一个非常简单的
goal increase user engagement make
目标：提高用户参与度，让
people spend more time on Twitter more
人们在Twitter、
time on Facebook engage more sending
Facebook上花费更多时间，增加互动，发送
more uh uh likes and recommending to
更多点赞，并推荐给
their friends why because the more time
朋友。原因很简单：
we spend on the platforms the more money
我们在平台上花费的时间越多，他们赚的钱就越多。
algorithms made a huge huge Discovery by
算法通过
experimenting on millions of human
在数百万用户身上进行实验，取得了一项重大发现：
that if you want to grab human attention
要想抓住用户的注意力，最
the easiest way to do it is to press the
简单的方法就是激发他们的
fear button the hate button the greed
恐惧、仇恨和贪婪。于是，算法
button and they started recommending to
开始向
users to watch more and more content
用户推荐越来越多的内容。
full of hate and fear and greed to keep
充斥着仇恨、恐惧和贪婪的内容，目的是让
them glued to the screen
人们沉迷于屏幕，
and this is the deep cause of the
这正是
epidemic of fake news and conspiracy
假新闻和阴谋论泛滥的深层原因。
the defense of of the companies is we
这些公司的辩解是：我们
are not producing the
没有制作这些
content somebody a human being produced
内容。有人，一个人，炮制了
a hatefield conspiracy theory about
关于移民的仇恨阴谋论，这
immigrants and it's not us it's like a
不是我们干的。这有点像……
bit like I don't know the the the chief
我不知道，《
editor of the New York Times publishing
纽约时报》的总编辑
a hatefi conspiracy theory on the front
在报纸头版刊登了一篇仇恨阴谋论。
when you ask him why did you do it or
当你问他为什么要这么做，或者
you blame him look what you did he says
指责他做了什么时，他会说：“我什么都没做，
I didn't do anything I didn't write the
我没写那篇
piece I just put it on the front of the
文章，我只是把它放在了《
New York Times that's all that's nothing
纽约时报》的头版，仅此而已。”
it's not
这根本不是
nothing people are producing immense
小事。人们正在制造海量的
content the algorithms are the king
内容，算法成了造王者，
makers they are the editors now they
它们现在就是编辑。它们
decide what gets viewed sometimes they
决定哪些内容会被看到，有时它们
just recommend it to you sometimes they
只是给你推荐，有时它们甚至会
actually auto play it to you like you
自动播放给你。比如，
you you chose to watch some video at the
你选择观看某个视频，但
end of the video to keep you glued to
为了让你沉迷于
the screen the algorithm immediately
屏幕，算法会在
without you telling him it the algorithm
你不知情的情况下立即播放下一个视频。 算法会在
without you telling the algorithm the
你不告诉它的情况下
algorithm autop
自动
plays some kind of video full of fear or
播放一些充满恐惧或
greed just to keep you glued to the
贪婪的视频，只是为了让你目不转睛地盯着
screen it is the algorithm doing it and
屏幕。这是算法在做的，
this should be banned or this should at
这应该被禁止，或者至少应该受到
least be uh uh supervised and regulated
监督和监管。
and this is not free freedom of speech
这不是言论自由，
because the algorithms don't have
因为算法没有
speech uh yeah the person who produced
言论自由。是的，制作
the hatefield video I would be careful
Hatefield视频的人，我会谨慎地考虑是否要
about banning them but that's not the
封禁他们，但这并不是
problem it's the recommendation which is
问题所在，真正的问题是推荐机制。
the problem the second problem is that a
第二个问题是，
lot of the conversations now online are
现在很多在线对话都被
being overrun by Bots again if you look
机器人占领了。以
for instance at Twitter X as an example
Twitter为例，
so people often want to know what is
人们经常想知道哪些内容正在
trending what which stories get the most
流行，哪些故事最受
attention if everybody's interested in
关注。如果每个人都
in in a particular story I also want to
对某个特定故事感兴趣，我也想
know what everybody's talking
知道大家都在谈论什么。
about and very often it's the Bots that
很多时候，
are driving the conversation because a
推动对话的是机器人，因为某个
particular story initially gets a lot of
故事最初会获得大量
traction a lot of traffic because a lot
关注和流量，因为很多
of bots Retreat it and then people see
机器人会转发它，然后人们
see it and think they don't know it's
看到它，却以为自己不知道真相。 那是
Bots they think it's humans so they say
机器人，它们以为是人类，所以就说，
oh lots of humans are interested in in
哦，很多人都对
this so I also want to know what's
这个感兴趣，所以我也想知道
happening and this draws more attention
发生了什么，这吸引了更多关注。
this should be forbidden buts are uh
这应该被禁止。但是，
very basically you cannot have ai
基本上，你不能让人工智能
pretending to be human beings this is
假装成人类，这是
fake humans this is counterfeit humans
假人类，这是伪造的人类。
if you see activity online and you think
如果你在网上看到一些活动，你以为
it's human activity but actually it's
是人类的活动，但实际上是
bought activity this should be banned
购买的，这应该被禁止。这
doesn't uh uh uh harm the free speech of
不会损害
any human being because it's a bot it
任何人的言论自由，因为它是机器人，它
doesn't have freedom of
没有
speech I was thinking a lot about what
言论自由。我一直在思考
you said about these algorithms are
你说的这些算法
actually running running the world and I
实际上在运行，它们正在运行，我的
mean yeah so if the algorithms are
意思是，是的，如果算法
deciding what I see based on what I
根据我花时间看的东西来决定我看到什么，
spend my time looking at because they
因为它们想让
want to make you know the platforms want
平台
to make more money and if I have a
赚更多钱，如果我
innate sort of predisposition to spend
天生就倾向于花
more time focused on things that scare
更多时间关注让我害怕的事情，那么
then you just have to give me a couple
你只需要给我几年时间，
of years and every year that goes past
每一年过去，
I'll become more fearful more it
我就会变得更加恐惧，这就会
reinforces your own weaknesses I mean
强化你的恐惧。 我的意思是，
again it's like the food industry so the
这就像食品行业一样。
food industry discovered we liked food
食品行业发现我们喜欢高
with a lot of salt and and and fat in it
盐高脂肪的食物，于是就给
and gives it more to us and then it says
我们提供更多这类食物，然后说：“
but this is what the customers want what
这就是顾客想要的，
do they want from us it's the same thing
他们想要什么？” 这和现在的算法是一样的，
but even worse with these algor
但更糟糕的是，
algorithms that because this is the food
因为这些算法是
for the mind yes humans have a tendency
精神食粮。没错，人类确实有这种倾向：
that if something is very frightening or
如果某件事非常可怕或让
something fills them with anger they
他们充满愤怒，他们就会
they focus on it and they tell all the
专注于此，并告诉所有的
friends about it but to artificially
朋友。但人为地
amplify it it's not it just it's just
放大这种情绪，这不仅
not good for our Mental Health and
不利于我们的心理健康和
Social Health it is using our own
社交健康，反而是在利用我们自身的
weaknesses against us instead of helping
弱点来对付我们，而不是帮助
us deal with them is it fair to say now
我们应对它们。这么说是否公平？
this is me just jumping to conclusions a
我可能有点妄下结论了，
little bit but is it fair to say that in
但在一个
a world where you remove um restrictions
取消了对某些
around blocking certain characters
角色（比如
right-wing characters that are their
右翼角色）的限制的世界里，这些限制
messages maybe based on immigration Etc
可能基于他们的移民等信息，
you remove those restrictions so they're
他们被
all allowed on every platform and then
允许在所有平台上发布内容，然后
you program the algorithm to be focused
你又编写算法专注
on Revenue that eventually more people
于收入，最终会有更多的人
will become right-wing and I say that in
变成右翼分子。我说这话是……
part
部分
because it's it's a right-wing narrative
原因是，
to say that immigrants are bad and that
说移民是坏人是右翼的惯用伎俩。当然，
you know I'm not saying that the left
我不是说左翼就
are innocent because they're absolutely
无辜，他们当然也有错，
not but I'm saying that the fearful
但我的意思是，在我看来，这种
narratives the fear seems to come more
恐惧的论调似乎更多地
from the right in my opinion MH like
来自右翼。
especially in the UK it was the fear
尤其是在英国，人们恐惧
comes from immigrants and these people
移民，认为这些人会骗走
are going to take your money and all
你的钱等等。
these kinds of things um I I I think the
我认为
key issue is to not to label it as a
关键在于不要把移民问题贴上
right or left issue because again
左翼或右翼的标签，因为
democracy is a conversation and you can
民主是一种对话，而对话
have a conversation only if you have
只有在存在
several different opinions and it's I
多种不同观点的情况下才能进行。我
think it should be okay to have a
认为，就移民问题展开对话是完全可以的，
people should be able to have different
人们应该能够持有不同的
opinions about it uh that's fine the
观点。
problem starts when uh one side
问题在于，当一方
vilifies and and
妖魔化和
demonizes anybody who doesn't think and
诋毁任何不认同他们观点的人时，就会出现这种情况。
you see it to some extent from both
你会发现，双方在某种程度上都存在这种现象，
sides but in in the case of immigration
但在移民问题上，
so you would have these conspiracy
你会看到一些阴谋
theories that anybody who supports
论，比如，任何支持
immigration for instance they want to
移民的人都想
destroy the country they are part of
摧毁这个国家，他们是
this conspiracy to flood the country
这个阴谋的一部分，企图用移民淹没这个国家。
with immigrants and to change its nature
移民，以及改变其本质
and and whatever and this is the problem
等等，这就是
that uh democracy once you believe that
民主的问题所在：一旦你认为那些与你
people who don't think like you they are
想法不同的人
not just your political Rivals they are
不仅仅是你的政治对手，他们是
your enemies they are out to destroy you
你的敌人，他们想要摧毁你，
they intend to destroy your way of life
他们意图摧毁你的生活方式、
your group then democracy
你的群体，那么民主就会
collapses because there can be no way uh
崩溃，因为
between enemies democracy doesn't work
敌人之间没有办法，民主行不通。
it works if you think that the other
如果你认为
side is wrong but there are still
对方错了，民主或许还能运作，但其中仍然有很多
essentially good people who care about
善良的人，他们关心
the country who care about me but they
国家，关心我，只是他们的
have different opinions if you think
观点不同。如果你认为
that they are my enemies they try to
他们是我的敌人，他们试图
destroy me then the election becomes
摧毁我，那么选举就变成了一场
like a war because you're fighting for
战争，因为你是在为
your survival you would do anything to
生存而战，你会不惜一切代价
win the election because your survival
赢得选举，因为你的生存
is at stake if you lose you have no
岌岌可危。如果你输了，你没有
incentive to accept the verdict if you
动力接受结果；如果你
win you only take care of your tribe and
赢了，你只会照顾自己的部落，而
not of the enemy tribe what if you don't
不会照顾敌对部落。如果你不
believe the election is legitimate then
相信选举的合法性，那么
democracy can't
民主就无法
function uh this is the again the basic
运作。这再次说明了，基本的
democracy can't exist in just any it's
民主不能存在于任何地方，
like it's like a delicate plant that
它就像一株娇嫩的植物，
needs certain conditions in order to
需要特定的条件才能
survive and to flourish and one
生存和繁荣。
condition for instance is that you have
例如，其中一个条件是…… 你需要具备
information technologies that allows a
能够进行对话的信息技术；
conversation another condition is that
另一个条件是
you trust the institutions if you don't
你必须信任选举机构；如果你不
trust the institution of
信任
Elections it doesn't work and and a
选举机构，那就没办法了。 这行不通。
third condition is that you need to
第三个条件是，你需要
think that the people on the other side
认为政治光谱另一端的人
of the political divide they are my
是我的
rivals but they are not my enemies
对手，但他们不是我的敌人。
now with Democratic conversations is
现在民主党内部对话的问题在于，
because of this tendency to go to more
这种走向
extremes it creates the impression that
极端化的倾向，造成了一种
the other side is is an enemy and this
对方是敌人的印象。这
is a problem not just for the right also
不仅是右翼的问题，左翼也存在这个问题。
for the left that on both sides you see
在两党，你都能看到这种
this this uh uh uh feeling that the
感觉，觉得
other side is the is an enemy and that
对方是敌人，
its positions are completely
对方的立场完全不
illegitimate and if we reach that point
合法。如果我们走到那一步，
then the conversation
对话就会
collapses and it should be possible to
崩溃。我们应该能够就
immigration like gender like climate
移民、性别、气候
change without seeing the other side as
变化等棘手问题进行复杂的对话和讨论，而不把对方视为
an enemy which was possible for you know
敌人。这在过去
for Generations so why is it that now it
几代人中都是可以实现的。那么，为什么现在
seems to just become impossible to talk
似乎无法与
with the other side or to about
对方对话，或者谈论
anything we have a big election in the
任何事情呢？
United States this year very big one
今年美国将举行一场大选，非常重要的一场。
yeah do you think a lot about it uh yes
你对此思考很多吗？嗯，是的，
yes I mean it seems like a very L it
我的意思是，这看起来会
will be a coin TOS I mean like
是一场非常糟糕的选举。 我的意思是，就像
50/50 um you know elections become
五五开一样，你知道，
issue if there is a chance they will be
如果选举有可能是
the last
最后一次，而且
elections if one side is intends to
一方打算在掌权后
Simply change the rules of the game if
简单地改变游戏规则，那么选举就真的会成为一个生死攸关的问题。
existential because again democracy
因为民主的
works on the basis of self-correcting
运作基于自我纠正
mechanisms that this is the big
机制，这是
advantage of democracy over dictatorship
民主相对于独裁的最大优势。
in a dictatorship a dictator can make a
在独裁政权下，独裁者可以做出
lot of good decisions but sooner or
很多正确的决定，但
later they will make a bad decision and
迟早会做出错误的决定，而且
there is no mechanism in a dictatorship
独裁政权没有机制
to identify and correct such mistakes
来识别和纠正这些错误。
mistakes like Putin yeah there is just
比如普京犯的错误，
no mechanism in Russia that could say
俄罗斯根本没有机制可以指出
Putin made a mistake he should go he
普京犯了错误，他应该下台，
should let somebody else try a different
应该让其他人尝试不同的
course of action this is the great
做法。这就是
advantage of democracy you try something
民主的巨大优势：你尝试一种方法，如果
it doesn't work you try something else
行不通，就尝试另一种。
but the big problem is what if you
但最大的问题是，如果你
choose someone who then changes the
选择的人改变了
system neutralizes its self-correcting
制度，破坏了其自我纠正
mechanism and then you cannot get rid of
机制，那么你就无法再把
him anymore this is what happened for
他赶下台了。例如，委内瑞拉就发生了这种情况。
instance in Venezuela that or originally
最初，
Chavez and the chavista movement they
查韦斯和查韦斯主义运动是通过
came to power democratically people
民主方式上台的，人民
wanted to let's try this and now in the
想要…… 咱们来试试这个。就在
last elections a couple of weeks ago um
几周前的上次选举中，
the evidence is very very clear that
证据非常清楚地表
Maduro lost big time but uh he controls
明马杜罗惨败，但他控制着
everything the election committee
一切，包括选举委员会等等。
everything and he claims no I won and
他声称自己赢了，结果
the they destroyed Venezuela you know
他们毁了委内瑞拉。你知道，大约
it's something like a quarter of the
四分之一的
population fled the country which was
人口逃离了这个国家，而委内瑞拉
America before and they just can't get
以前可是南美洲最富裕的国家之一。他们就是摆脱不了他。
get rid of the guy surely that will
这肯定
never happen in the west oh don't say
不会发生在西方吧？哦，别说
never in history uh uh history can can
永远不会，历史上什么都有可能发生。历史总会
catch up with you whoever you are that's
追上你的，不管你是谁。这是我们的
one of the Illusions we Venezuela was
错觉之一。委内瑞拉曾经是
part of the West in in many ways still
西方的一部分，在很多方面现在仍然
is this is one of the Illusions we live
是。这是我们生活在其中的错觉之一，
under though we think oh that that can
尽管我们认为这永远不会
never happen to the UK or the United
发生在英国、美国
States or Canada these sort of of quote
或加拿大这些所谓的“
unquote civilized Nations you know
文明国家”。你知道，
According to some measurements democracy
根据一些衡量标准，美国的民主制度
in the United States is quite new and
相当新，也相当
quite quite fragile if you think about
脆弱，比如从
it in terms of of who gets to vote for
谁有投票权的角度来看。
instance so um it's yeah it would be
所以，嗯，
again I don't know what are the chances
我不知道可能性有多大。
but even if there is a 20% chance that a
但即便特朗普政府有20%的可能性
trump Administration would change the
会改变
rules of the game of American democracy
美国民主的游戏规则，比如
instance by uh uh changing the rules
改变
about who votes or how do you count
投票权或计
votes H that it will become almost
票方式，以至于几乎
impossible to get rid of them uh that's
不可能将其赶下台，这并非完全不可能，
in historical
从历史
terms do you think it's possible that
角度来看，你认为
Trump will do that yes I mean you saw it
特朗普会这么做吗？是的，我的
on the 6th of January I mean the the the
意思是，1月6日那天就发生了。
most sensitive moment in in every
在任何
democracy is the moment of transfer of
民主国家，
power and the magic of democracy is that
权力交接都是最敏感的时刻，而民主的魅力就在于它
democracy is meant to ensure a peaceful
旨在确保权力的和平
transfer of power that as I said like
交接。就像我刚才说的，
you choose one party you give them a try
你选择一个政党，给他们一段
after some time if people say they
时间，如果人们说他们
didn't do a good job let's try somebody
做得不好，那就换一个。
else and you know you have people who
你知道，在
hold in the United States they hold the
美国，有些人掌握着
biggest power in the world the president
世界上最大的权力。
of the United States have enough power
美国总统拥有足以
to destroy human civilization
摧毁人类文明的权力——所有
all these nuclear missiles all this Army
这些核导弹，所有这些军队。如果
and he loses the election and he says
他输掉选举，他说，
okay I give up all this power and I let
好吧，我放弃所有这些权力，我让……
the other guy try this is this is
其他人也试过这个，这真是太
amazing and this is exactly what Trump
不可思议了，而这正是特朗普
didn't do he from the beginning I mean
从一开始就没做到的。我的意思是，
even from 2016 he refused they they
甚至从2016年起，他就拒绝接受选举结果。当人们
asked him directly if you lose the
直接问他，如果输掉
election will you accept the results and
选举，他会接受结果吗？
he said no and um in 2020 he did not
他回答“不”。而且，在2020年，他没有
hand power peacefully he tried to
和平交出权力，而是试图
prevent it and the fact that he is now
阻止权力交接。而现在他又要
running again and I I think to some
竞选连任了。我认为，在某种程度上，
extent the lesson he got from the sixth
他从1月6日事件中吸取的教训
of January is that I can basically get
是，我基本上可以为所欲为，
away with anything at least with my
至少在我的
people with my base that it was like a a
支持者面前是这样。这就像一次
a test a try if I do this extreme thing
测试，如果我做了这种极端的事情，
and they still support me
而他们之后仍然支持我，
afterwards it basically means they will
那就意味着
support me no matter what I do I'm I'm
无论我做什么，他们都会支持我。我在
wondering in a world of um such a
想，在一个如此
fragile democracy when information Flows
脆弱的民主世界里，当信息流动
In networks are disrupted by something
在网络中被
like AI if misinformation and
人工智能之类的东西扰乱，当错误信息和
disinformation and the ability for me to
虚假信息传播，而我
make a video I could make a video right
又能制作视频时——我现在就可以制作一段
now of Donald Trump speaking and saying
唐纳德·特朗普讲话的视频，
something in his voice um and I could
用他的声音说些什么——我可以
help that video go viral like how do you
让这段视频迅速传播开来。那么，当你对网上看到的一切都不相信时，你该如何
hold
维系
together democracy and communication
民主和沟通呢？
you're seeing online H and we're just at
我们
the start of this now so I we haven't
现在才刚刚开始，所以我们还没
seen anything yet this is just really
看到任何东西，这真的只是
the the first baby steps I'm going to
最初的几个步骤。我
play a video on the screen right now so
现在要在屏幕上播放一段视频，这样
people can see and for those listening
大家就能看到了，而那些正在收听的人只能
you'll just hear it but I'm going to
听到声音。我要
play a video that Isaac over there in
播放一段视频，是
the corner of the room made of me
房间角落里的艾萨克拍的，视频里我坐在
speaking in this chair and it wasn't me
椅子上说话，但那不是我，
and I didn't say it and I wasn't in this
我说的也不是我，我当时也不在那把
chair hey there this is AI Steve do you
椅子上。嘿，大家好，我是AI史蒂夫，你们
think I'll be able to take over the dire
觉得我有一天能接任
of a CEO one day leave your comments
CEO的职位吗？请在
below and it sounds EX like me identical
下方留言。这听起来跟我一模一样，
and it's not me and I I wonder this with
但那不是我。我很好奇，
you know mo most of us get our political
你知道，我们现在大多数人获取政治
information and our information
信息和其他信息
generally now from social media yeah
主要来自社交媒体。是的，
from and if I can't believe anything
来自……如果我无法相信
that I'm seeing because it's all easy to
我看到的任何东西，因为
make some kid in Russia in their bedroom
制作视频太容易了，俄罗斯的某个孩子在卧室里
could make a video of the Prime Minister
就能拍出总理的视频……
here um I don't know where we get our
我不知道我们现在从哪里获取
information from anymore how we the
信息了。
answer is institutions we've been in
答案是机构。历史
this situation many times before in
上我们多次遇到过这种情况。
history and the answer is always the
总是
same institutions you cannot trust the
同样的机构。你不能相信
technology you trust the institution
技术，你只能相信
that verifies the information think
验证信息的机构。想想纸质媒体，
print that um you can write on a piece
你可以在
of paper anything you want you can write
纸上写任何你想写的东西，比如“
the prime minister of Britain said and
英国首相说”，
then you open quotation marks and you
然后加上引号，
put something into the mouth of the
把一些话强加到
Prime Minister you can write anything
首相的口中。你可以写任何
you want and when people read it they
你想写的东西，但人们读到后
don't believe it or they they shouldn't
不会相信，或者说他们不应该
believe it just because it's written
相信。仅仅因为上面写着“
that the prime minister said it doesn't
首相说”，并不
mean that it's true so how do we know
意味着那就是真的。那么，我们如何知道应该
which pieces of paper to believe as an
相信哪些纸质媒体呢？作为
institution we would believe or greater
机构，
chance we will believe if on the front
如果《
page of the New York Times or of the
纽约时报》、《
Sunday Times of the Guardian you will
星期日泰晤士报》或《卫报》的头版
have the British prime minister said
刊登“英国首相说”之类的文章，我们更有可能相信，
because we don't trust the paper or the
因为我们不相信报纸或
Inc we trust the institution of the
机构本身，我们相信的是《
guardian of the or the Wall Street
卫报》、《华尔街
Journal or whatever
日报》或其他媒体机构。
with videos we never had to do that
对于视频，我们以前不需要这样做，
because nobody could fake them so we
因为没人能伪造视频。所以我们
trusted the technology if we saw a video
相信技术，如果看到视频，
we said ah this is this has to be true
我们会说“啊，这一定是真的”。
but when it becomes very easy to fake
但当伪造视频变得如此容易时，情况就不同了。
videos then we revert to the same
然后我们又回到了
Principle as with Sprint we need an
和Sprint一样的原则：我们需要一个
institution to verify it if we see the
机构来验证。如果我们
video on the official website of CNN or
在CNN或《华尔街日报》的官方网站上看到视频，
of the Wall Street Journal than we
我们就会
believe it because we believe the
相信，因为我们相信
institution backing it and if it's just
支持它的机构。但如果只是
something on Tik Tok we know that you
TikTok上的内容，我们都知道
know any kid can do that why why should
任何孩子都能做到，那
I believe it so now we are in the
我为什么要相信呢？所以现在我们正处于
transition period we are still not used
过渡期，我们仍然
to it so when we see a video of Donald
不习惯。当我们看到唐纳德·
Trump or Joe Biden the video still gets
特朗普或乔·拜登的视频时，这些视频仍然会让
to us because we grew up in a time when
我们感到震惊，因为我们成长在一个
it was impossible to fake it but I think
不可能造假的时代。但我认为
very quickly people will realize you
人们很快就会意识到，你
can't trust videos you can only trust
不能相信视频，你只能相信
institutions and the the question is
机构。问题是，
will we be able to produce uh to create
我们能否足够快地建立和
to maintain trustworthy institutions
维护值得信赖的机构来
fast enough to save the Democratic
挽救民主
conversation because if not if you can't
对话？因为如果不能，如果你
believe anything this is the ideal for
什么都不能相信，那对独裁者来说就是理想的状态。
dictators uh uh when you can't trust
当你什么都不能相信时，
anything the only system that works is a
唯一有效的制度就是
dictatorship because democracy works on
独裁，因为民主建立在
trust but dictatorship works on terror
信任之上，而独裁建立在恐怖和
on fear you don't need to trust anything
恐惧之上。在独裁统治下，你不需要相信任何东西。 在
in a dictatorship you don't trust
独裁统治下，你什么都不信任，
anything you
你
fear uh for democracy to work you need
害怕。民主要想运作，你需要
to trust for instance that some
信任，例如，某些
information is reliable that the
信息是可靠的，
election committee is impartial that the
选举委员会是公正的，
courts are just and uh uh if more and
法院是公正的。如果越来越
more institutions are attacked and
多的机构受到攻击，
people lose trust in them then then then
人们对它们失去信任，那么
democracy collapses uh but going going
民主就会崩溃。回到
back to to to information so one option
信息本身，一种选择
is that the old institutions like
是，像
newspapers and TV stations uh uh they
报纸和电视台这样的传统机构，它们
will be the institutions that we trust
将成为我们信任的、用来
to verify certain videos or we will see
验证某些视频的机构；或者我们会看到
the emergence of new
新的
institutions and the again the big
机构出现。而最大的
question is whether uh we'll be able to
问题是，我们能否
develop trust in them and I specifically
建立起对它们的信任。我特意
say institutions and not
强调的是机构，而不是
individuals no large scale soci Society
个人。没有值得信赖的官僚机构，任何大规模的社会，
especially not a Democratic Society can
尤其是民主社会，都无法
function without trustworthy
运转。
institutions and will those bureaucratic
这些官僚机构会是人工智能吗？
institutions be AI That's the big
这是一个关键
question because increasingly AIS will
问题，因为越来越多的官僚机构将由人工智能来扮演。
bureaucrats and what do you mean by
你说的官僚是什么意思？“官僚”这个
bureaucrats what's the word bureaucrat
词是
what does that mean oh uh that that's a
什么意思？哦，这是一个
very important question because uh uh
非常重要的问题，因为
human civilization runs on bureaucracy
人类文明的运转离不开官僚机构。
bureaucrats are essentially officient in
官僚本质上是
government that TR not just in
政府的官员，不仅仅是
government it's I mean the origin of the
政府官员。我的意思是，“
word bureaucrat it comes from French
官僚”这个词源于
from the 18th century and bureaucracy is
18世纪的法语，而“官僚主义”
is means the the rule of the writing
指的是
Society with pen and papers and
用笔、纸和
documents like the example we gave in
文件来统治世界或社会。就像我们一开始举的
ownership so there you own a house
所有权例子一样，你拥有一栋房子，是
because there is a document in some
因为某个档案馆里有一份文件
archive that says that you own it and a
证明你拥有它，而这份文件是由
bureaucrat produced this document and if
官僚出具的。如果
you now need to retrieve it then this is
你现在需要找回这份文件，那么
the job of of a bureaucrat to find the
官僚的职责就是
right document at the right time and all
在正确的时间找到正确的文件。所有的
big uh uh uh systems run on it hospitals
大型系统都依赖于这些文件运行——医院
and schools and corporations and Banks
、学校、公司、银行、
and and sports associations and
体育协会、
libraries they they all run on these
图书馆等等。所有这些机构都依赖这些文件运转。
know how to read and write write and
懂得读写、撰写、
find and file
查找和归档
documents one of our big problems is
文件的官僚们，正是我们理解官僚体系的关键所在。我们面临的一大问题是，
that it's it's it's difficult for us to
我们很难
understand bureaucratic systems because
理解官僚体系，因为这是
human evolution and this makes us
人类进化史上一个非常近期的发展阶段，这让我们
suspicious about them and we tend to uh
对它们抱有怀疑，并且我们往往会……
believe all kinds of uh uh conspiracy
相信各种
theories about the Deep State and about
关于“深层政府”以及
what what's going on in all these
所有
bureaucracies
官僚机构内部运作的阴谋论，
and it's really complicated and it's
这真的很复杂，而且
going to be more complicated as more of
随着越来越多的
the decisions will be made by AI
决策由人工智能
bureaucrats and AI bureaucrat means that
官僚做出，情况会变得更加复杂。人工智能官僚意味着，
decisions like how much money to
像给
allocate to a particular issue will no
某个特定问题分配多少资金这样的决定将
longer be made by a human official it
不再由人类官员做出，
will be made by an algorithm and when
而是由算法做出。当
people decide why when people ask why is
人们问为什么
the switch system broken why didn't they
开关系统坏了，为什么
why didn't they give enough money to fix
他们没有拨出足够的钱来修复
it
它时，
I don't know the algorithm just decided
我不知道，算法只是决定把
to give the money to something else why
钱拨给其他用途。为什么
will bureaucracies be run by AI over
官僚机构会由人工智能而不是人来管理？
people like why will at some point a
为什么某个国家会在某个时候
nation decide that in fact AI can is
意识到人工智能实际上可以
better at making these decisions first
更好地做出这些决策？
of first of all it's not a future
首先，这不是未来的
development it's already happening more
发展趋势，它已经发生了。
and more of the decisions are being made
越来越多的决策正在
by AIS and this is just because the
由人工智能系统做出，这是因为
amounts of information you need to take
需要考虑的信息量非常
into account are are enormous
庞大，
and it's very difficult for humans to do
人类很难做到，而
it it's much easier for the AIS to do it
人工智能系统则容易得多。
if all these people you know bureaucrats
这些人，你知道的，官僚、
lawyers accountants it sounds like I I
律师、会计师，听起来我
always wonder you know what are humans
总是在想，你知道，人类最终还能
going to be left to do in your book you
做什么？你在书中
say that AI is going to
说人工智能发展过头了，它
far AI is going so far beyond human
远远超越了人类智能，
intelligence that it should actually be
以至于应该
referred to alien intelligence now if it
称之为外星智能。如果它真的
goes so far beyond human intelligence
远远超越了人类智能，那么
we do is based on intelligence so even
我们所做的大部分工作都是基于智能的，这很正常。所以，即使像
like me doing this podcast now this is
我现在做这个播客，
me asking questions based on information
我提出的问题也是基于
that I've gathered based on what I think
我收集的信息，基于我认为
I'm interested in but also based on what
自己感兴趣的东西，也基于
I think the audience will be interested
我认为听众会感兴趣的东西。
in and compared to AI I'm a like a
与人工智能相比，我就像一只
little monkey like I you know what I
小猴子，你知道我的
mean if if an AI has an IQ that is 100
意思吗？如果一个人工智能的智商是
times mine in in source of information
我的100倍，信息来源
that is a fat million times bigger than
比
mine there's no need for me to do this
我的大一百万倍，那我就没必要做这个
podcast I can get an AI to do it and in
播客了，我可以找人工智能来做。
fact an AI can talk to an AI and deliver
事实上，人工智能可以和人工智能对话，并将
that information to a human but then if
信息传递给人类。但是，如果
we look at most Industries like being a
我们看看大多数行业，比如
lawyer um accountancy I mean a lot of
律师、会计师，我的意思是，很多
Med the medical profession is based on
医疗行业都是基于
information um driving I think that's
信息的。 我认为
the biggest employer in the world is the
世界上最大的雇主是
profession of driving whether it's
司机这个职业，无论是
delivery or Uber or whatever it is um
送货司机、优步司机还是其他什么
accountants lawyers doctors they are the
司机。在这个复杂的系统中，人类究竟扮演着什么角色？任何仅仅是信息输入和输出的工作都非常适合自动化。这些工作
easiest to automate if a doctor the only
最容易实现自动化，比如程序员，或者会计师（至少某些类型的会计师）、律师、医生等等。如果医生的工作
thing they do is just take information
仅仅是接收
in all kind of results of blood tests
各种信息，比如血液检测结果
and whatever and they information out
等等，然后输出信息，
the they diagnose the disease and they
诊断疾病并开处方，那么
to automate in the coming years and
在未来几年甚至几十年内，这些工作都很容易实现自动化。
decades but a lot of jobs they require
但是很多工作
also social skills and motor skills if
还需要社交技能和运动技能。如果
your job requires a combination of
你的工作需要结合
skills from several different fields
多个不同领域的技能，虽然
it's it's not impossible but it's much
并非不可能，但
more difficult to automate it so if you
自动化难度要大得多。例如，
think about a nurse that needs to
想想看，一个护士需要给
replace a bandage to a crying child this
哭闹的孩子换绷带，这比
just a doctor that writes a prescription
医生开处方要难得多，
because this is not just data the nurse
因为这不仅仅是数据处理。护士
needs uh uh good social skills to
需要良好的社交技能来
interact with the child and motor skills
与孩子互动，还需要运动技能来
to just replace the
更换绷带。
bandage um so this is harder to
绷带，嗯，所以这很难
automate and uh there will even for
自动化，而且即使是那些
people who just deal with information
只是处理信息的人，
there will be new jobs the problem will
也会有新的工作机会。问题在于
be the retraining and not just you know
再培训，不仅仅是
retraining in terms of of acquiring new
学习新技能方面的再培训，
skills but psychological retrain
还有心理上的再
training how do you kind of reinvent
培训。你如何
yourself in a new profession and do it
在新的职业中重塑自我，而且
not once but again and again and again
不是一次，而是一次又一次地这样做，
because as the AI Revolution unfolds and
因为随着人工智能革命的展开——
we have just at the very beginning of it
我们才刚刚开始，还
we haven't seen anything yet so there
没有看到任何迹象——
will be old jobs disappearing new jobs
旧的工作会消失，新的工作会
emerging but the new jobs will rapidly
出现，但新的工作会迅速
change and vanish and then there will be
变化和消失，然后又会出现
a new wave of new jobs and people will
新一波新的工作，人们
have to reinvent themselves four five
必须重塑自我四五
six times to stay relevant
六次才能保持竞争力，
and this will create immense
这将造成巨大的
psychological
心理
stress so many of the big companies are
压力。所以很多大公司同时也在
also working at the same time on
研发
humanoid robots there's this humanoid
人形机器人，一场人形
robot race going on and by humanoid
机器人竞赛正在进行。说到人形
robots I mean you know Tesla have their
机器人，我的意思是，你知道，特斯拉正在研发他们的
humanoid robot I think it's called Optus
人形机器人，我想它叫Optus，
which they're developing and it'll cost
价格要
you know X thousands of pounds and and I
几千英镑。我
watched a video of it recently where it
最近看过一个视频，它
can do quite delicate sort of motor
能做一些相当精细的事情。 一些需要动手
skill based stuff so probably clean the
能力的工作，比如打扫
house it can probably work on the
房子，可能可以在
production line can probably put things
生产线上工作，可能可以把东西
in boxes
装箱。
um and I just wonder when we say you
嗯​​，我只是在想，当我们说
in a world where you have humanoid
在一个拥有人形
robots and you have intelligence that's
机器人和超越人类智能的世界里，人们会失业，而
these humanoid robots are very very
这些人形机器人又非常非常
intelligent I go I don't know what I'm
智能时，我就不知道该怎么办了。
like where did the the unemployed go to
失业的人都去哪儿
to to find these new professions like
找这些新职业了？
obviously it's it's difficult to
显然，
forecast the new professions of the
预测未来的新职业很难，
future history tells us then but I but I
历史会告诉我们答案，但我搞
can't get I can't figure out what the
不清楚，我搞不清楚这些新职业到底是什么。
new professions are I mean my girlfriend
我的意思是，我女朋友
does breath work I guess the breath work
做呼吸练习，我觉得呼吸练习
part is quite easy to disrupt but then
很容易被打断，但
she takes women away for retreats in
她会带一些女性去
Portugal and stuff so I'm like okay
葡萄牙之类的地方参加静修活动，所以我想，好吧，
she's going to kind of be safe because
她应该会比较安全，因为
these women are going there to connect
这些女性去那里是为了
with humans and to be in this little
与人交流，
special place offline intentionally so
刻意地到一个特殊的、与世隔绝的地方。所以，
Retreats she'll probably be fine yeah
静修活动她应该没问题。是的，
anything that you know there are things
你知道，
that we want in life which are not just
生活中我们想要的东西不仅仅是
about solving problems like I'm sick I
解决问题。 我生病了，我
want to be healthy I want my problem
想恢复健康，我想解决我的问题，
solved but there are
但是，
uh um many things that we want to have a
嗯，有很多事情我们都想建立
connection like if you think about
联系，比如想想
sports um robots or or or machines can
体育运动，机器人或机器
run much faster than people for a very
跑得比人快得多已经
long time now and we just had the
很久了，而且我们刚刚结束了
Olympics and people are not very
奥运会，人们
interested in seeing robots running
对看机器人
against each other or against people
互相比赛或与人比赛并不感兴趣，
because what really makes Sports
因为体育运动
interesting in the end is the human
最终真正吸引人的是人类的
weaknesses and the ability of humans to
弱点以及人类
to deal with their
克服这些
weaknesses and and human athletes still
弱点的能力。
have jobs even though in in again in
即使在
many lines like running you can have a
跑步等很多领域，
machine run much faster than the world
机器跑得比世界
champion I thought about this the other
冠军快得多，人类运动员仍然有工作。我前几天就想到了这一点。
day and uh uh and another example is is
嗯，另一个例子是
priests like one of the easiest jobs to
牧师，至少在某些宗教中，牧师是最容易自动化的工作之一，
certain religions because you just need
因为你只需要在
again and again in in specific
特定
situations like if you have a wedding
情况下一遍又一遍地重复相同的经文和手势，比如在婚礼
ceremony then um you know the priest
仪式上，牧师
just need to repeat the same words and
只需要重复相同的词句，你就
there you are you're married now we
结婚了。我们
don't think about priests as being in
不会认为牧师有被
robots um because what we want from a
机器人取代的危险。 嗯，因为我们对
priest is not just the mechanical
牧师的期望不仅仅是机械地
repetition of certain words and
重复某些词句和
gestures we think that only
手势。我们认为，只有
another frame flesh and blood human who
另一个有血有肉的人，一个
knows what is pain and love and and who
懂得痛苦和爱，
can suffer only they can connect us to
能够承受苦难的人，才能将我们与
the Divine so most people would not be
神灵连接起来。所以，大多数人不会对
conducted by a robot even though
由机器人主持婚礼感兴趣，即使从
technically it's very easy to do it now
技术上讲，这很容易做到。
the big question of course what happens
当然，现在最大的问题是：
if AI gains Consciousness this is like
如果人工智能获得了意识会发生什么？这就像
the trillion dollar question of of of AI
一个价值万亿美元的问题——人工智能的意识。
Consciousness then it's all bets are off
一旦人工智能拥有意识，一切都将变得不可预测。
but that's a a different and very very
但这又是一个截然不同且非常
big discussion I mean whether it's
庞大的讨论。我的意思是，这是否
possible how would we know and and so
可能？我们如何才能知道？
forth do you think it's
等等。你认为这有
possible we have no idea I mean we don't
可能吗？我们一无所知。我的意思是，我们不
understand what Consciousness is we
理解意识是什么，我们
don't know how it emerges in the organic
不知道它如何在有机
brain so we don't know if there is an
大脑中产生。所以我们不知道
Consciousness and organic
意识和有机
biochemistry so that it can't arise in
生物化学之间是否存在本质联系，以至于它无法在
an inorganic uh silic based computer
无机的硅基计算机中产生。
there is a big confusion first of all
首先，
should be said again between
应该再次强调的是，
Consciousness and
意识和
intelligence um intelligence is the
智能之间存在很大的混淆。智能是
ability to reach goals and solve
达到某种境界的能力。 目标和解决
problems Consciousness is the ability to
问题。意识是
feel things like pain and pleasure and
感受痛苦、快乐、
love and
爱与
hate humans and other animals we solve
恨等情绪的能力，包括人类和其他动物。我们
problems through our feelings our
通过感受来解决问题。
feelings are not something on the side
感受并非无关紧要，而是我们
they are a main method for how to deal
应对
with the world how to solve
世界、解决
problems now so far
问题的主要方式。然而，就目前而言，
computers they solve problems in a
计算机解决问题的方式与
completely different way than humans
人类截然不同。
again they are alien intelligence they
它们是外星智能，它们
don't have any feelings when they win a
没有任何感觉。即使它们赢得游戏，它们也不会有任何感觉。
they lose a game they are not sad they
他们输掉比赛时并不高兴，也不难过，他们
don't feel anything now we don't know
什么感觉都没有。我们现在还不知道
how organic brains produce these
有机大脑是如何产生
feelings of pain and pleasure and love
痛苦、快乐、爱
and hate so this is why we don't know
和恨这些感觉的。所以，我们不知道
silicon and not carbon whether it will
基于硅而不是碳的无机结构是否
be able to generate such things or not
能够产生这些感觉。
that's I think the biggest question in
我认为这是科学领域最大的问题，
in in science and um so far we have no
而且到目前为止我们还没有
answer isn't Consciousness just like a
答案。意识难道不就像
hallucination isn't it just like an
幻觉吗？难道不就像一种
illusion that I think I'm conscious
错觉吗？我以为自己有意识，是
because I've got at the circuitry which
因为我感觉到了大脑的回路，它通过一系列感觉
tells me that I am effectively it tells
告诉我我有意识，比如
things that I'm conscious like I think
我觉得
I'm looking at you now I think I can see
我现在正在看着你，我觉得我能看到
you the feeling is real I mean even if
你，这种感觉是真实的。我的意思是，即使
we are all it's like the Matrix and we
我们都身处其中，就像身处《黑客帝国》一样，
are all in how do you know it's real
你怎么知道它是真实的？
it's the only real thing in the world I
它是世界上唯一真实的东西吗？我的
mean there is nothing I everything else
意思是，没有其他任何东西，其他一切都
is just conjuncture we we only
只是巧合。我们只
experience our own feelings what we see
体验我们自己的感觉，我们看到的，
what we
我们闻到的，
smell what what we touch this we
我们触摸到的，这些才是我们
actually experience this is real then we
真正体验到的。 如果这是真的，那么我们就会有
have all these theories about why do I
很多关于“我为什么会
feel pain oh it's because I stepped on a
感到疼痛”的理论，比如“因为我踩到了
nail and there is such a thing in the
钉子”，而世界上确实存在钉子这种东西。
world as a nail and whatever it could be
不管是什么，
that we are all inside that a big
我们都身处一个位于
computer on the planet ziron run by
齐龙星球上的大型计算机中，而这个计算机是由
superintelligent mice if I spoke to an
超级智能老鼠运行的。如果我跟
AI I could get an AI to to tell me that
人工智能对话，它就能告诉我
it feels pain and sadness that's that
它感受到了疼痛和悲伤，仅此而已。这就是
that's the that's a big problem because
问题所在，因为人们
there is a huge incentive to train AIS
有巨大的动机去训练人工智能，让它假装
to pretend to be alive to pretend to
活着，假装
have feelings and and and we see that
有感情。我们看到，人们投入了
there is a huge effort to to to to
大量精力来
produce such AIS and in truth because we
制造这样的人工智能。事实上，因为我们
don't understand Consciousness we don't
不了解意识，我们甚至没有
have any proof even that other humans
任何证据证明其他人也
have
有
feelings I feel my own feelings but I
感情。我能感受到自己的感受，但我
never feel your feelings I only assume
从未感受到你的感受。我只是假设
that you're also a conscious being and
你也是一个有意识的生命体。
Society grants uh this a status of a
社会赋予了这种
conscious
意识
entity to not only to humans but also to
实体的地位，不仅赋予了人类，也赋予了
some animals not based on any scientific
一些动物，但这并非基于任何科学
proof but based on social
证据，而是基于社会
convention like most people feel that
习俗。比如，大多数人认为
their dogs are conscious that their dogs
他们的狗有意识，他们的狗
can feel pain and pleasure and love and
能感受到疼痛、快乐和爱。
so forth so Society accepts most
如此一来，大多数社会都接受
societies that dogs are sentient beings
狗是有感知能力的生物，
and they have some rights under the law
并且它们现在享有法律赋予的一些权利。随着
now as AI become even if AI has no
人工智能的发展，即使人工智能本身没有任何
feelings no consciousness no sentience
感觉、意识或感知能力，
whatsoever but it becomes very good at H
但它却非常擅长
uh pretending to have feelings and
假装有感觉，并让
convincing us that it has feelings then
我们相信它有感觉，那么
this will become a a social convention
这将成为一种社会惯例，
that people will feel that their AI
人们会觉得他们的人工智能
friend is is a conscious being and
朋友是有意识的生物，
therefore should be granted rights and
因此应该被赋予权利。
there is even already a legal path for
甚至
how to do it at least in the United
在
States you don't need to be a human
美国，已经存在着实现这一目标的法律途径——你不需要是人类才能
being in order to be a legal person it's
成为法律意义上的人。这很
funny because you mentioned you kind of
有趣，因为你刚才提到，你半开玩笑地暗示
alluded to the fact jokingly that we
我们
might just be in like a simulation it
可能只是生活在一个模拟世界里。
was one of you like well maybe we're
你们中的一个人说，也许我们
just in a simulation but could be and
只是生活在一个模拟世界里，但有可能。
it's funny because in a world of AI I
有趣的是，在人工智能的世界里，我
think my belief in that as a possibility
认为这种可能性
has only increased this is in fact just
只会增加。这实际上只是
a simulation because I've watched us go
一个模拟世界，因为我亲眼见证了我们从
from when I was born not really having
出生时几乎没有
internet access to now being being able
互联网接入，到
computer that can like now do things for
现在能够通过电脑与这个可以做各种事情的“外星人”对话。
me and having virtual reality
我体验过虚拟现实，有时感觉和现实世界几乎
indistinguishable where my my you know I
无法区分，你知道，我很容易
fall into the Trap of believing that I
陷入这样的陷阱：
am inside squid games because I've got
我戴着
this headset on and you play it forward
头显，玩着游戏，感觉自己真的置身其中。
and you play it forward and you play it
你一遍遍地玩，
forward and you imagine any rate of
想象着游戏不断
improvement then I hear the the
改进，然后我听到了
arguments for simulation Theory and I go
模拟理论的论点，我想，
do you know probably if you play this
如果按照
years you know like at the rate we're on
我们目前的发展速度，把游戏推演一百年，我们或许
will be able to create information
就能创造出信息
networks and organisms that don't in
网络和生物体，它们并非生活在
like a laboratory or in a computer that
实验室或电脑里，它们甚至不一定
don't necessarily realize yeah they're
意识到自己身处
computer especially with like what's
电脑之中。尤其是在现在这种现象
going on with it's already happening to
已经出现的情况下，
bubbles that more and more people live
越来越多的人生活在信息泡沫中。虽然
inside them it's still not the whole
这还不是整个
physical world but you get the same
物理世界，但同样的事件发生后，
event and people on say different parts
不同
of the political political spectrum they
政治立场的人却
just can't agree on anything they live
无法达成任何共识，他们生活
in their own metries MH and you know the
在各自的世界里。你知道，当
the when when when the internet came
互联网第一次出现的时候，
along for the first time the main
主要问题就出现了。
metaphor was the web the worldwide web a
隐喻是网络，万维网，
web is something that connects
网络连接着
everything and now the main metaphor
一切。现在，主要的隐喻，也就是
simulation theory is is is is is is
模拟理论，
representing this new metaphor the new
代表着这个新的隐喻。这个新的
metaphor is the cocon it's a web that
隐喻是茧，它是一张会
turns on you and en closes you from all
反过来困住你的网，从四面八方将你包围，让
sides so you can no longer see anything
你再也看不到
outside and there could be other cocoons
外面的世界。而且可能还有其他茧，
with other people in there and you have
里面装着其他人，你根本
no way to get to them yeah no nothing
无法联系到他们。是的，
that happens in the world can connect
世界上发生的任何事情都无法再将
you anymore because you're in different
你与外界联系起来，因为你身处不同的
cocoons you've only got to look at
茧中。你只需要看看
someone else's phone you've only got to
别人的手机，
look at someone else's Twitter or X or
看看别人的推特、Xbox或
Instagram is this the same reality it is
Instagram，这还是同一个现实吗？
so different I do you know what I was
完全不同。你知道我
talking about over the weekend my friend
周末说的是什么吗？我朋友在
was at to my left scrolling he clicked
我左边刷手机，他点开了“
on the Discovery section which is where
发现”版块，就是那个可以
you find new content I looked down at
找到新内容的地方。我低头看了看
his phone and was like it's all
他的手机，发现全是
Liverpool Football Club it's like the
利物浦足球俱乐部的内容，
entire feed is Liverpool and my entire
整个信息流都是利物浦，而我的
feed is completely different and I was
信息流完全不同。我当时
just thinking wow he lives in a
就想，哇，他生活在一个
completely different world to me because
和我完全不同的世界里。 因为
he's a Liverpool fan I'm a Manchester
他是利物浦球迷，我是
United fan and and it's yeah just and to
曼联球迷，所以，
think about that like to think that when
想想看，当
you open your phone and many of us are
你打开手机时——我们很多人
spending up to 9 hours a day on our
每天在手机上花费长达9个小时——
mobile phones you're experiencing a
你看到的是一个与
completely different world than I am and
我截然不同的世界。
and this was you know this this is a
这是一种
very ancient fear because um for
非常古老的恐惧，因为，
instance Plato wrote exactly about that
例如，柏拉图
in the most famous Parable I think from
在他最著名的寓言——洞穴
Greek philosophy is the the allegory of
寓言——中就写到了这一点。
the cave in which PL
柏拉图
imagines a theoretical scenario an
想象了一个理论场景：
imaginary scenario of of a group of
一群
prisoners chained inside a cave with
囚犯被锁在一个洞穴里，
their face to a blank wall in which
脸贴着一面空白的墙壁，墙壁上
Shadows are being projected from behind
投射出影子，
them and they mistake the shadows for
他们把影子误认为是
reality and he was basically describing
现实。他基本上是在描述
you know people in front of his screen
屏幕前的人们把
just mistaking the screen for reality
屏幕误认为是现实。
and you have the same thing in Ancient
在古
India with Buddhist and Hindu sages
印度，佛教和印度教的圣贤也
talking about uh uh Maya which is the
谈到过“摩耶”（Maya），也就是
Illusions and the Deep fear that maybe
幻象的世界，以及
we are all trapped inside a world of
我们可能都被困在一个
illusions that the the most important
幻象世界中的深切恐惧。我们最重要的
thing that we think in the world uh the
事情是…… 想想看，
the wars we fight we fight Wars over
我们打的仗，其实是为
Illusions in our
我们
mind and uh this is now becoming
头脑中的幻象而战。现在，这在
technically possible like previously it
技术上已经成为可能。以前，这只是
was these philosophical thought
哲学思想
experiments now part of what is
实验。
interesting as a historian about the
作为一名历史学家，我对
present era is that a lot of ancient
当今时代感兴趣的地方在于，许多古代
philosophical problems and discussions
哲学问题和讨论
are becoming technical
正在变成技术
issues that yes you can suddenly realize
问题。是的，你甚至可以突然
PLO cave in your
在
phone so scary I find it really scary
手机上看到巴解组织的崩溃。这太可怕了，我觉得真的很可怕，
because you're right like I think right
因为你说得对。我觉得
now some people might say that they have
现在有些人可能会说，他们对
some kind of grasp over like the ranking
排名
system or why something shows up when I
系统或者
search it or whatever but as these
搜索结果的显示方式之类的有所了解。但是，随着这些
intelligence aliens become more and more
外星智能变得越来越
powerful um it's of course we would have
强大，我们当然会越来越
less understanding because we're like
不了解，因为我们
handing over the decision in some
在某些行业中就像是把决策权拱手让给了他们。
Industries they are now completely the
他们现在完全是
king makers like I'm here on a book tour
幕后操纵者。比如我现在正在进行新书巡回宣传，
I wrote Nexus so I go from podcast to
我写了《Nexus》，所以我挨个播客、挨个
podcast from TV station to TV station to
电视台
talk about my book
宣传我的书。
but the the the entities I'm really
但我真正
trying to impress of the algorithms M
想打动的是算法，
because if I can get the attention of
因为如果我能吸引到
the algorithms the humans will
算法的注意力，人类就能得到关注。 会
[Laughter]
[笑声]
follow H yuck uh you know that's that's
跟随H yuck呃，你知道，这就是
our real we are basically kind of carbon
我们的真实情况，我们基本上是
creatures in a silicon world I used to
硅世界里的碳基生物。我以前
think we were in control though and now
认为我们掌控着一切，但现在
I feel like the Silicon in control
我觉得硅掌控着一切，
uh control is Shifting that that's we
呃，控制权正在转移。
are still in control to some extent we
在某种程度上，我们仍然掌控着一切，我们
are still making the most important
仍然在做出最重要的
decisions but not for long and this is
决定，但这不会持续太久。这就是
why we have to be very very careful
为什么我们必须非常非常谨慎地
about the decision we make in the in the
对待
next few years because uh in 10 years in
未来几年做出的决定，因为呃，10年、
10 in 20 years it could be too late by
20年后，可能就太晚了，到
then the algorithms will be making the
那时算法将做出
most important decisions you talk about
最重要的决定。你谈到了
the algorithms in Ai and the sort of
人工智能算法带来的几个重大危险，以及
shift and disruption of information one
信息的转移和混乱，其中之一就是
of them is this alignment
对齐
problem which um how would you explain
问题。呃，你会如何用简单易懂的
the alignment problem to me in a way
方式向我解释对齐问题呢？一个
classical uh kind of example is a
经典的例子是
philosopher Nick Bostrom in 2014 which
哲学家尼克·博斯特罗姆在2014年提出的一个思想实验，
sounds crazy but but you know bear with
听起来很疯狂，但请耐心听我说。呃，
it um he imagines a super
他设想了一个 假设一家回形针工厂买下了一台超级
intelligent uh AI computer which is
智能的人工智能计算机。
paperclip manager tells the AI your goal
工厂经理告诉人工智能：“
the reason I I bought you your goal your
我买下你的目标就是
produce as many paper clips as as
生产尽可能多的回形针，
possible that's your goal and then the
这就是你的目标。”然后，
AI conquers the entire world kills all
人工智能征服了整个世界，杀死了所有
humans and turns the entire planet into
人类，把整个星球变成了
factories for producing paper clips and
生产回形针的工厂。
it even begins to send itions to outer
它甚至开始向外太空发射指令，试图把
space to turn the entire galaxy into
整个银河系都变成
just paperclip production
回形针生产
industry and the point of the thought
基地。这个思想
experiment is that the AI did exactly
实验的重点在于，人工智能完全按照
what it was told it did not rebel
指示行事，没有反抗
against the humans it did exactly what
人类，完全按照
the boss wanted but of course it was not
老板的意愿行事。当然，
the the strategy it chose was not
它选择的策略与
Factory manager who just couldn't
工厂经理的真实意图和利益并不一致，经理根本无法预见到
foresee that this will be the result now
这样的结果。
this sounds like outlandish and
这听起来匪夷所思、荒谬可笑，
ridiculous and crazy but it already
但这种情况
happened to some extent and we talked
在某种程度上已经发生过，我们也讨论过。
about it this is the whole problem with
这就是
social media and user engagement in the
社交媒体和用户参与度面临的问题。就在
very same years that Nick Bostrom came
尼克·博斯特罗姆
up with this thought experiment in 2014
于2014年提出这个思想实验的同一年，
the managers of Facebook and YouTube
Facebook的经理们……  YouTube
they told their algorithms your goal is
告诉他们的算法，目标是
to increase user engagement and the
提高用户参与度。
algorithms of social media they
社交媒体的算法
conquered the world and turned the whole
征服了世界，并将整个
world into user engagement which was
世界都变成了用户参与的温床，这正是
what they were told to do we are now
他们被告知要做的事情。我们现在
very very
非常非常
engaged and again they discover that the
活跃，但他们又发现，
way to do it is with outrage and with
实现这一目标的方法是煽动愤怒、
fear and with conspiracy theories and
恐惧和阴谋论。
this is the alignment problem when Mark
这就是问题所在。当马克·
Zuckerberg told the Facebook algorithms
扎克伯格告诉Facebook的算法要
increase user engagement he did not
提高用户参与度时，他没有
foresee and he did not wish uh that the
预料到，也不希望
result will be collapse of democracies
结果是民主制度崩溃、
wave of conspiracy theories and fake
阴谋论和假
news hatred of minorities he did not
新闻泛滥、对少数族裔的仇恨。他并非
intend
有意如此。但
it uh but this is what the algorithms
算法却造成了这样的结果，
did because there was a
因为
that was defined to the algorithm and
算法的目标与
the interests of of human society and
人类社会的利益，
even of the human managers of of the
甚至与
companies that that are deployed these
部署这些
algorithms and this is still as a small
算法的公司管理者的利益之间存在着错位。这仍然是一场小
scale
规模的
disaster because the social media
灾难，因为
social chaos over the last 10 years they
在过去十年里制造了所有这些社会混乱的社交媒体算法，
are very very primitive
是非常原始的
AI this is like the the amibas of if you
人工智能，就像Amiba一样。
think about the development of AI as an
关于人工智能的发展，我们可以将其视为一个
evolutionary process for this is still
进化过程，因为它目前仍处于
the amoeba stage the amoeba being the
变形虫阶段。变形虫是
very simple the very simple life forms
生命形式中最简单的阶段，
the the beginning like a single cell
就像单细胞
life form we are still in evolutionary
生命体一样，处于进化的初期。从进化的
terms organic evolution we are like
角度来看，我们仍然处于有机进化阶段，距离
dinosaurs and the mamals or the humans
恐龙、哺乳动物或人类的出现还有数十亿年的时间。然而，
but digital evolution is billions of
数字进化的速度
times faster than organic evolution so
比有机进化快数十亿倍，因此，
the AI dinosaurs could be covered in
人工智能从变形虫阶段发展到恐龙阶段，可能只需
just a few decades if CH GPT is the
几十年就能完成。如果将CH GPT视为变形虫阶段，那么
amiba how would the AI Tyrannosaurus Rex
人工智能霸王龙会是什么样子呢？
like and this is where the alignment
这正是目标一致性
problem becomes
问题变得
disconcerting because if so much damage
令人不安的地方。如果给
goal to A Primitive social media
一个原始的社交媒体算法赋予错误的目标都会造成如此大的破坏，那么
T-Rex AI in 20 or 30 years the issue at
在20或30年后，给一个霸王龙人工智能赋予一个错误的目标又会造成怎样的后果呢？问题的
the heart of this is you know some
核心在于，有些
people might think okay just give it a
人可能会认为，好吧，那就给它设定一个
different goal but when you're dealing
不同的目标。但是，当你在
with private companies who are listed on
与上市的私营公司打交道时，
the stock market there really is only
实际上只有
one goal that keep that exactly that
一个目标。 保持这种有
benefits survival so all of the
利于生存的原则，所有
platforms have to say you know the goal
平台都必须承认，
of this platform is to make more money
他们的目标是赚更多钱，
and to get more attention because also
获得更多关注，因为
it's mathematically easy and there is a
这在数学上很容易实现。然而，
huge huge problem in how to define for
如何为人工智能和算法定义目标却存在一个巨大的难题，即如何让
they can understand now the the great
它们理解这个目标。
thing about make money or increase user
赚钱或提高用户
engagement is that it's very easy to
参与度的好处在于，它很容易用
measure it mathem atically MH uh one day
数学方法衡量。比如，YouTube 上某天
you have a million hours being watched
有 100 万小时的观看时长，
on YouTube then next a year later it's 2
一年后就达到了
million very easy for the algorithm to
200 万小时，算法很容易就能
see hey I'm making progress but let's
看出“嘿，我在进步”。但是，假设
say that that Facebook would have told
Facebook 告诉
its algorithm increase user engagement
它的算法，要以一种
in a way that doesn't undermine
不损害
democracies how do I measure that who
民主的方式提高用户参与度，我该如何衡量这一点呢？谁
knows what is the definition for the
知道民主稳健性的定义是什么？
robustness of De of democracy nobody
没人
knows
知道。
so defining the go of the algorithm as
因此，将算法的目标定义为“提高
increase user engagement but don't harm
用户参与度，但不损害
democracy almost
民主”几乎是
impossible this is why they go for the
不可能的。这就是为什么他们选择那些
most dangerous but even in that scenario
最危险、也最容易实现的目标。即使在这种情况下，
if I told if I'm the owner of a social
如果我是一个社交网络的拥有者，
network and I say increase user
我说“提高用户
engagement but don't harm democracy the
参与度，但不损害民主”， 民主的
problem I have is my competitor who
问题是，我的竞争对手
leaves out the second part and just says
忽略了第二部分，只说要
increase user engagement is going to
提高用户参与度，这样就能
beat me because they're going to have
击败我，因为他们会拥有
more users more ibles more Revenue
更多用户、更多内容、更多收入，
advertisers are going to be happier then
广告商会更满意，而
my company is going to falter investors
我的公司会举步维艰，投资者
are going to pull out that's a question
会撤资。这是一个问题，
because there are two things to take
因为有两件事需要
into consideration first of all uh you
考虑。首先，
have governments governments can
政府可以
regulate and they can penalize a social
监管，他们可以惩罚那些以对社会负责的方式
media company that defines goals in a
设定目标的社交媒体公司，
socially responsible way just as they
就像他们
penalize newspapers or TV stations or or
惩罚那些行为反社会的报纸、电视台或
or or car companies that uh behave in an
汽车公司一样。
antisocial way the other thing is that
其次，
uh um humans are not stupid and
人类并不愚蠢，也不会
self-destructive that uh uh if we we
自我毁灭。如果我们想要
would like to have better products in
更好的产品，也想要对
the sense of also socially better
社会更有益的
products and I I gave earlier the
产品，我之前举过
example with food diets like think how
食品的例子。想想看，
much yes the food companies they
食品公司
discovered that uh uh if they fill a
发现，如果他们在
product artificially with lots of fat
产品中人为地添加大量的脂肪
and sugar and salt people would like it
、糖和盐，人们会喜欢它，
but people discovered that this is bad
但人们发现这对
for their health so you now have a like
他们的健康有害。所以现在人们喜欢……
for instance a huge market for diet
例如，减肥产品市场巨大，
products and people are becoming very
人们越来越
aware of what they eat the same thing
关注自己的饮食。同样的情况也
can happen in the information Market the
可能发生在信息市场。
cost though is like 80 70 80% of people
然而，代价是，美国有70%到80%的人
in the US have like chronic disease and
患有慢性疾病，而且
are obese and you know life expectancy
肥胖。你知道，西方世界的预期寿命似乎正在
is now looks like it's going the other
下降。我
and it's I don't know I just feel like
不知道，我只是觉得，
policing consumption of goods like
监管
alcohols nicotine food seems much more
酒精、尼古丁和食品等商品的消费似乎
simple than policing
比监管
information and the flow of
信息和
information Beyond you know beyond
信息流动要简单得多。除了
racism or like inciting
种族主义或煽动
violence I don't know how you
暴力之外，我不知道该如何
police we already covered the the two
监管。我们已经讨论过，
most basic and Powerful uh tools are to
最基本、最有效的两个工具是让
hold companies liable for the actions of
公司为其算法的行为负责，而
their algorithms not for the content
不是
that the users produce but for the
用户发布的内容，而是
actions of the algorithms uh I don't I
算法的行为。我
don't think we should penalize Twitter
不认为我们应该惩罚Twitter
or Facebook if somebody post uh a a
或Facebook，如果有人发布了
racist post um I would be very careful
种族主义帖子。我会非常谨慎地对待
about penalizing Facebook for that
惩罚Facebook，
because then who decides what is racism
因为那样的话，谁来决定什么是种族主义
and so forth but if the algorithm of of
等等。 但如果
Facebook deliberately spreads some
Facebook的算法故意传播
racist conspiracy theory that's the
种族主义阴谋论，那是
algorithm that's not human Free Speech
算法，不是人，这关乎言论自由。
how do you know it's a racist conspiracy
你怎么知道它就是种族主义阴谋
theory though okay so now now we get to
论呢？好吧，现在我们来
the to the difficult conversation but
谈谈这个棘手的问题。
this is something that we have the
这个问题我们可以诉诸
courts for and I would be very very
法庭。我会非常
careful about having the courts judge on
谨慎地让法庭来评判
individual
单个
users but when it comes comes to uh
用户发布的内容。但是，当
algorithms deliberately routinely
算法故意、例行地
spreading a particular type of of
传播特定类型的
information like a conspiracy theory we
信息，比如阴谋论时，我们
can involve the courts the the key issue
可以诉诸法庭。关键问题
is who has liability that it's the
在于谁应该承担责任。应该为
algorithm is doing and not the human
算法的行为负责的是公司，而不是
individual liable for what they are
为自己的言论负责的个人。
saying um and another key distinction
另一个关键的区别在于
here is between private and public
私人和公共领域。
like part of the problem is the Erasure
问题的一部分在于
of the boundary between the two I think
两者之间的界限被抹杀。我认为，
that humans have a right to stupidity in
人们在
private that in your private space with
私人空间里有权说蠢话。在和朋友、家人相处的私人空间里，
you have a right to stupidity you can
你有权说蠢话。你可以
say stupid things you can tell racist
讲种族主义
jokes you can tell homophobic jokes it's
笑话，你可以说恐同言论。 开玩笑
not good it's not nice but you're a
不好，也不好，但你是
human being you're allowed to do that
个人，你有权利这么做，
but not in public
只是不能在公共场合。
I mean even for politicians like as a
我的意思是，即使是政治人物，比如我作为一个
gay person if the Prime Minister tells a
同性恋者，如果首相私下里讲了个
a homophobic joke in private I don't
恐同的笑话，我不需要
need to care about that that's his or
关心，那是他/
her business but if they say it in
她的私事。但如果他们在
public on on television that's a huge
电视上公开说，那就成了大
problem now traditionally it was very
问题。传统上，
easy to distinguish private from public
区分私下和公开场合很容易。
you are in your private house with a
你在自己家里和
group of friends you say something
一群朋友说了些
stupid that's private it's n Nobody's
蠢话，那是私事，与他人无关。但
you go to the town square and you stand
你去到广场，站在
on on a pedestal and you shout something
台上对着
to thousands of people that's public
成千上万的人大喊大叫，那就是公开场合了。
here you can be punished if you say
如果你说了
something racist or homophobic of
种族歧视、恐同或
outrageous but it it was easy for you to
出格的话，你可能会受到惩罚。但以前很容易
know now the problem is you go let's say
分辨。现在的问题是，比如说，你
on WhatsApp you think you're just
在WhatsApp上，你以为只是在
talking with two of your friends and you
和两个朋友聊天，然后你
say something really really stupid and
说了些非常非常蠢的话，
then it it gets viral and it's all over
结果它迅速传播开来，到处都是，
the place and and uh I don't have an an
呃，我没有
easy solution for that but um
简单的解决办法。 就此而言，
one one measure which is adopted by some
一些政府采取的一项措施
governments is for instance that uh uh
是，例如，
people who have a large following they
拥有大量粉丝的人与
people who don't even on the the most
粉丝较少的人适用不同的标准，甚至在
basic thing of identifying yourself as a
最基本的自我识别方面也是如此。
being uh we don't want that everybody
我们不希望每个人都必须
would have to get some certification
获得
from the government to talk with their
政府的某种认证才能在
friends on on WhatsApp but if you have a
WhatsApp上与朋友聊天，但如果你在
100,000 followers online we need to know
网上有10万粉丝，我们需要知道
that you are not a bot that you're
你不是机器人，你
actually a human being and again this is
确实是真人。再次强调，这
not covered by freedom of speech because
并不属于言论自由的范畴，因为
Bots don't have freedom of speech the
机器人没有言论自由。这很危险，
slippery slope right because I've I've
因为我一直在
gone back and forth on this argument of
纠结于
anonymity and whether it's a good thing
匿名性
or a bad thing for social networks and
对社交网络究竟是好是坏。
the rebuttal that I got when I lent to
当我倾向于要求用户提供身份信息时，得到的反驳
the side of um iding people is that like
是，
totalitarian governments will use that
极权政府会利用匿名性来
as a way to basically punish the people
惩罚那些敢于发声的人。
governments are doing it whether we like
无论我们是否喜欢，极权政府都在这样做。这
it or not it's it's not a question that
不是一个问题。 如果
if the British do it then the Russians
英国人这么做，俄罗斯人
will say okay so we'll also do it the
就会说好，那我们也跟着做。
Russians are doing it anyway will
反正俄罗斯人本来就在这么做，
Americans start to do it will they start
美国人会不会也开始这么做呢？
to if if someone speaks out against
如果有人公开反对
Trump and he has access to their
特朗普，而他又掌握了他们的
identity and information can he go look
身份信息，他能不能去调查
at them and get them
他们，把他们
arrested if we reach that point when the
逮捕？如果我们到了
courts will allow such a thing then we
法院允许这种事发生的地步，那我们已经
are in very deep trouble
非常麻烦了。
already and uh what we should realize is
我们应该意识到，
that with the surveillance technology
有了现在的监控技术，
now in existence a totalitarian
极权
government has so many ways to know who
政府有很多方法可以知道
you are that it's that's not the the
你是谁，所以这并不是
main issue right you talked about um the
主要问题，对吧？你刚才提到了
platforms being responsible for the
平台应该为
consequences yes in the UK over the last
后果负责。是的，过去
month we've had I don't know if you've
一个月，英国发生了骚乱，我不知道你有没有
heard that we had of riots and um I
听说。我
think it was all triggered originally
认为这一切最初的导火索是
someone had murdered some young children
有人谋杀了一些幼童。
yes and there was a confusion or sort of
确实，当时
a misinformation around that person's
围绕那个人的
religion and that meant that people Pro
宗教信仰存在一些误解或错误信息，这意味着人们……
that's an excellent example because you
这是一个很好的例子，因为你
know if I personally privately say to
知道，如果我私下里
just two of my friends I think the
只跟两个朋友说“我觉得那
person who did it is ex I don't think we
个人是前任，我不认为我们应该……
should be you should be persecuted for
你不应该为此受到迫害”，
that I could say it in my private living
我可以在自己家里的客厅里说，
on WhatsApp or or on Facebook but if a
在WhatsApp或Facebook上说也一样。但如果
Facebook
Facebook的
algorithm picks up this piece of fake
算法抓取了这条假
news and starts recommending it to more
新闻，并开始向越来越
and more users then Facebook is liable
多的用户推荐，那么Facebook就要
for the action of its algorithms you can
为其算法的行为负责。
you should be able to take it to court
你可以把它告上法庭，
and say the algorithm deliberately
说算法故意
recommended a piece of fake news
推荐了假新闻。
and again if if the fake news was
而且，如果这条假新闻是
produced by an influencer with a million
由一个拥有百万
followers then it's also his he is also
粉丝的网红炮制的，那么他也应该为此
liable for that but if if a private
负责。但如果一个
individual in a private setting uh um
普通人在私下场合
said something which is not true it's
说了些不实之词，那就是
fake
假
news and then an algorithm deliberately
新闻，然后算法故意
spread it the main fault is with the
传播了它，那么主要责任在于
algorithm and the people who should be
算法，应该
in jail are the managers of the company
坐牢的是拥有这个算法的公司的管理人员，
that owns this algorithm and not the
而不是那
individual who uttered the words going
个人。 假设有人在骚乱当天发表了那番言论，而骚乱的起因是《
don't know the guardian on the day of of
卫报》当天
of the riots decided to pick up a piece
刊登了一条
of of this fake news and publish it on
假新闻，并将其放在
its front
头版。
page and they now go take the editor of
现在，有人将《
the Guardian to court and he says but I
卫报》的编辑告上法庭。编辑辩解说：“我
didn't write it I just found this piece
没有写这条假新闻，我只是发现了它，
of fake news and decided to put it on
然后决定把它放在《卫报》
the front page of the
的头版上。” 显然，
that the editor did something very very
这位编辑犯了非常非常严重的
very wrong and he might or she might
错误，他/她可能要
have to sit in jail and it's not the
坐牢。这并非是
problem of the person who originally
最初炮制假新闻的人的问题。
produced the piece of fake news if
如果
you're the editor of one of the biggest
你是全国发行量最大的报纸之一的编辑，
decide to publish something on your
决定在
front page you had better be very very
头版刊登某些内容，你最好非常非常
sure that what you're publishing is the
确定你发布的内容是
truth especially if it can incite to
真实的，尤其是一些可能煽动
violence how would a social network
暴力的内容。社交网络的运营
owner know that how would they be able
者如何才能知道这一点？他们如何在
that scale not everything but if uh for
如此大规模的传播中核实所有内容的真实性？当然，并非所有内容都如此。例如，如果
instance something is likely to lead to
某些内容可能导致
violence and the very first it's a
暴力，那么首先，
precautionary principle first of all do
预防原则是：
no no harm again I'm I'm not asking
不要这样做。 别担心，我不是要求
Facebook to
Facebook
censor the piece of fake news I'm only
审查这条假新闻，我只是
asking it don't get your algorithms to
要求它不要
spread it on purpose in order to get
为了提高
user engagement and make a lot of money
用户参与度和赚取巨额利润而故意让算法传播它。
if you are not sure about it just don't
如果你不确定，就不要
spread it it's as easy as that how does
传播，就这么简单。
it know it's fake news versus it
它怎么知道这是假新闻，还是
thinking that it's actually really
真的
important life- saving news so for
救命新闻？举个
example that's the responsibility of of
例子，这是公司的责任。就像《
the editor of the Guardian know or of
卫报》的编辑、《
the financial times or of the Sunday
金融时报》的编辑、《星期日
times how do they know if something is
泰晤士报》的编辑一样，他们怎么知道某件事是真是
true and if something should be
假，是否应该
published on the front page if you are
发表在头版？如果你
now managing a social media company you
现在管理一家社交媒体公司，你也
are managing one of the most powerful uh
管理着世界上最有影响力的
uh newspapers in the world and you
报纸之一，你
should have the same kind of
应该承担同样的
responsibilities and the same kind of
责任，拥有同样的
expertise if you have no idea how to
专业知识。如果你不知道如何
judge whether an algorithm should
判断算法是否应该向
recommend something to millions of
数百万人推荐某件事，那你
people you in the wrong business you
入错行了。如果你
know if you can't stand the heat get out
受不了压力，就别干这
of the kitchen don't run a social media
行，
company if you don't know what should be
如果你不知道什么才是最重要的，就别经营社交媒体公司。
shown to millions of people one of the
向数百万人展示过，
it's very P because obviously Mark
这非常复杂，因为显然，马克·
Zuckerberg's letter that he wrote this
扎克伯格本周写的信中
week says I was approached by the FBI
提到，联邦调查局联系了他，
who told me that Russia were trying to
告诉他俄罗斯试图
in influence the elections and they were
影响选举，并向他们
given some information that there was
提供了一些信息，说
this laptop story Joe um Joe Biden
乔·拜登和他的
Hunter Biden who Joe Biden's son had
儿子亨特·拜登的笔记本电脑里有相关内容。Facebook当时
this laptop story which Facebook didn't
不
know if it was real or not and they
知道真假，他们
thought maybe it was a Russian um plant
认为这可能是俄罗斯的阴谋，
I Russia had put the story there to try
俄罗斯放出这条消息是为了
and make sure Joe Biden didn't win the
阻止乔·拜登赢得
elections so Facebook deprioritized it
选举。因此，Facebook降低了这条消息的优先级，
stopped it going viral and suppressed it
阻止其传播并压制了它。结果证明这是
turns out it was a real story and it
真的，
wasn't fake and Mark Zucker says he
并非虚假消息。马克·扎克伯格表示，他
regrets suppressing it because it was in
后悔压制了这条消息，因为它
fact a real real story and in
确实是一个真实的故事，而
suppressing it he kind of in influenced
压制它在
the election to some degree mhm um so
某种程度上影响了选举。嗯，所以情况
it's so complicated to the point that I
非常复杂，以至于
just complicated to run a big Media
运营一家大型媒体
Company it's complicated to run the Wall
公司都变得非常复杂，运营《
Street Journal or Fox News again what
华尔街日报》或福克斯新闻也是如此。
happens if if the FBI comes to Fox News
如果联邦调查局找到福克斯新闻
or comes to the Wall Street Journal and
或《华尔街日报》，并
tells them look there is this story
告知他们……会发生什么？ 他们看看，这个故事是
planted by the Russians don't encourage
不是俄罗斯人捏造的？别助长这种风气，
it and later on it turns out that it was
后来发现是
wrong um could happen and as the manager
错的。嗯，这种情况可能会发生。作为《
of the Wall Street Journal you need to
华尔街日报》的经理，你需要
deal with it and do I trust the FBI
处理这件事。我该信任FBI吗？
under what conditions sometimes I should
在什么情况下我应该信任？
sometimes I should be suspicious I feel
有时候我应该保持怀疑。我觉得
like you're can end up in jail H you're
你最终可能会坐牢。你是《
the editor of the Wall Street Journal
华尔街日报》的编辑，
you're gonna end up in jail either way
无论如何你最终都会坐牢，
because either way you're influencing
因为无论如何你都在影响
elections and if you influ but that's
选举。如果你影响了选举，这就是
the business I mean the real problem is
生意。我的意思是，真正的问题是，
like zukerberg or Elon Musk that pretend
像扎克伯格或埃隆·马斯克这样权力极大的人，却假装
that they don't have power that they
他们没有权力，
don't have influence that they don't
没有影响力，没有左右
shape shape elections we know for
选举。几个
centuries that the owners and editors of
世纪以来，我们都知道报纸的所有者和编辑
newspapers they shave elections and
会影响选举，
therefore we hold them to certain
因此我们对他们有一定的
standards and now the owners and
要求。现在，
managers of platforms like Twitter and
像推特、
YouTube and Facebook they have more
YouTube和脸书这样的平台的拥有者和管理者，他们的
power than the New York Times or the
权力比《纽约时报》、《
guardian or the Wall Street Journal and
卫报》或《华尔街日报》更大，
they should be held to at least the same
他们至少应该承担同样的
degree of accountability and their stick
责任。他们不应该说“
that oh we are just a platform we just
哦，我们只是……” 我们
allow everybody to publish what they
允许任何人随意发布内容，
want it doesn't work like that and we
这样的平台行不通。
don't accept it with traditional media
传统媒体不接受这种做法，
so why should we accept it with that's
为什么我们要接受这种做法呢？这就是
that's the whole trick of these tech
这些科技
companies that again we have thousands
公司的惯用伎俩。他们说，我们拥有数
of years of history and they tell us oh
千年的历史，但这些规则
it doesn't apply to us like if you have
不适用于我们。比如
a traditional industry like cars it's
汽车这样的传统行业，
obvious to everybody you cannot put a
大家都明白，
new car on the road unless you made some
新车上路前必须经过
safety checks to make sure the car is
安全检查，确保
safe you cannot put a new medicine in
安全；新药
the on the market or a new vaccine on
或新疫苗上市前也必须经过
the market without safety that's obvious
安全测试，这显而易见。
right but when it comes to algorithms no
但算法就不一样了，
rules H you can put any algorithm you
规则完全不同。你可以把任何算法
want on the market you don't need any
推向市场，不需要任何
safety rules and even more basic than
安全规则。更基本的道理是，
that you think about something like
想想
theft you have the Ten Commandments
盗窃，有十诫，
don't
不可
steal and you know people know yes you
偷盗，大家都知道不
shouldn't steal until it comes to
应该偷盗。但
information ah no no no it doesn't apply
信息就不一样了，他们说不通。
to information I can can take your
我可以未经
information and without your permission
你允许就拿走你的信息，
do all kinds of things with it and sell
做各种各样的事情，甚至卖给
it to third parties and this is not
第三方。  “不
stealing don't steal doesn't apply to my
偷窃，不偷窃”这条原则不适用于我的
line of business and this is what the
行业。
cases over the last decade or two
过去一二十年里，科技巨头们在很多情况下都在这么做，他们
telling us that history doesn't apply to
告诉我们历史对他们不适用，
them that all the wisdom that Humanity
人类在几个世纪甚至几千年里，以
gained in a very painful way over
极其痛苦的方式
dealing with dictatorships and with uh
与独裁政权和其他种种斗争中积累的所有智慧，
uh uh whatever it doesn't apply to the
都不适用于
new technology and and it does it does
新技术。但事实并非如此，它确实
apply do you ever feel tempted to just
适用。你有没有想过干脆
log off and just like go live in a field
断网，去某个地方隐居，
somewhere maybe like a desert maybe just
比如沙漠，甚至
create a little bit of a cult and I do
建立一个小团体？我
it every year oh really yeah I take a
每年都这么做。真的吗？是的，我会进行一次
days and 60 days uh like this year I
到60天的长时间冥想静修。比如今年，我
plan in December after the book tour is
计划在12月新书巡回宣传结束后，去
retreat in India and just completely
印度进行为期60天的冥想静修，彻底
disconnect no smartphone no internet not
断网，不用智能手机，不用网络，
even books or or or or or writing paper
甚至不用书本或纸张，
just just the information fast why it's
只接收信息，为什么这
good for the mind uh again like with
对心灵有益？就像
food too much in isn't good for us we
食物一样，摄入过多对我们不好，我们
need time to digest and to detoxify and
需要时间消化。 排毒，对
it's true of of the mind as well if you
心灵也一样。如果你
just keep bombarding it with
不断地用更多信息轰炸它，
more um it's you get addicted to the
你就会沉迷于
wrong WR things you develop bad habits
错误的东西，养成​​坏习惯。
and um you need or at least I need um
你需要，或者至少我需要，
time off in order to really kind of
休息一段时间，才能真正
digest everything that happened and to
消化所有发生的事情，才能
um decide what I want and what I don't
决定我想要什么，不想要什么，应该
should I should try to to to to be rid
尝试戒掉哪些习惯和瘾。同时，
of and also to you know to get to know
你也需要时间来了解
my own mind when the mind is constantly
自己的内心。当心灵不断被
outside
外界信息轰炸时，
you it's so
它会变得非常
noisy you cannot get to know it because
嘈杂，你无法了解它，因为
there is so much noise but when the
噪音太多了。但是，当
noise uh uh is is goes
噪音
away then you can start to understand
消失时，你就可以开始理解
what is the mind how does it function
什么是心灵，它是如何运作的，它是
how does it work where do thoughts come
如何运作的，思想从何而来，
from what is fear what is anger when
什么是恐惧，什么是愤怒。当
you're boiling with anger because of
你因为
something you just you now read you are
刚刚读到的某些事情而怒火中烧时，你
focused on the object of your anger but
专注于愤怒的对象，但
you can't understand the anger itself
你无法理解愤怒本身。
the anger controls
愤怒控制着
you when you have an information
你。当你拥有信息时，
fast you can just observe what happens
你可以观察会发生什么。
to me when I'm angry what happens to to
当我生气的时候，
to my mind to my body how does it
我的思想和身体会发生什么变化？它如何
control me and this is more important
控制我？这
than any angry story in the world to
比世界上任何关于愤怒的故事都重要，因为
understand what anger actually is it's
理解愤怒的本质
it's very very difficult I mean how many
非常非常困难。我的意思是，有多少
times do people stop and just you know
人会停下来，
try to get to know their anger and not
试着去了解自己的愤怒，而不是
the object of the anger this we do all
愤怒的对象？我们总是这样做，我们会反复
the time we kind of Replay we we heard
回想我们听到的某个
something terrible that a politician we
我们不喜欢的政客的糟糕言论，比如，
don't like like I don't know somebody's
有人
angry about Trump so he would replay it
对特朗普很生气，所以他会一遍遍地回想，
again and oh he said like this he did
哦，他说过这样的话，他做过那样的事，
like that he will do this he will do
他会做这个，他会做
that and you don't get to know your
那个。但你无法通过这种方式了解你的
anger that way I have about 50 different
愤怒。我现在在Flight Group旗下有大约50家不同的
companies in my portfolio at flight
公司，其中
group now some of which I've invested in
一些是我投资的，一些是
and some of which I've co-founded or
我联合创立的，还有一些是我
founded myself one thing I've noticed is
自己创立的。我注意到的一点是，
that most companies don't put enough
大多数公司
effort into their hiring process in my
在招聘流程上投入的精力不够。在我
mind the first and most critical thing
看来，商业中最重要的事情
in business is assembling your group of
是组建团队，
people because the definition of the
因为“
word company is group of people and
公司”这个词的定义就是一群人。在
throughout all of my companies whenever
我所有的公司中，我都这样做。 每当
I'm looking to hire someone my first
我需要招聘人才时，我的首选
Port of Call is LinkedIn jobs who I'm
就是LinkedIn Jobs。我很高兴地
happy to say are also a sponsor of this
告诉大家，LinkedIn Jobs也是本播客的赞助商。
podcast they've helped us Source
他们帮助我们
professionals who we truly can't find
找到了其他任何地方都找不到的专业人才，
anywhere else even those who aren't
甚至包括那些目前没有
actively searching for a new job but who
积极寻找新工作，但
might be open to a perfect role in fact
可能对理想职位持开放态度的人。事实上，
over 70% of LinkedIn users don't visit
超过70%的LinkedIn用户不会访问
other leading job sites so if you're not
其他主流招聘网站。所以，如果你不在
looking on LinkedIn you're probably
LinkedIn上找工作，那你可能
looking in the wrong place so today I'm
找错地方了。今天，我将为
giving the dire of the CEO Community a
CEO社区的成员们提供一个
free LinkedIn job post head to
免费的LinkedIn职位发布机会。请访问
linkedin.com
linkedin.com，立即发布职位，
doac now and let me know how you get on
并告诉我你的体验。
terms and conditions
条款和条件
apply so interesting I was playing out
适用。很有意思，
the scenario in my head as you speaking
在你谈到未来时，我一直在脑海中设想这样一个场景：
these two species of human you have one
人类几乎分为两类。一
species of human who are connected to
类人通过大脑
internet through the neuralink in their
中的神经连接（Neuralink）与互联网上的信息高速公路相连，就像上了
brain that's just like they're hooked
瘾一样，
and the algorithm is feeding them
算法不断地向他们推送
information and they're acting upon it
信息，他们根据这些信息采取行动，然后再将信息传递给算法。
this other group of people who decided
另一类人则选择了
to reject that who didn't get the
拒绝这种连接，他们没有获得
neuralink who aren't trying to interface
神经连接。 那些不试图
with AI and that are living in a tribe
与人工智能交互，生活在
in some jungle somewhere and I like my
某个丛林部落里的人，就像我
girl said this to me many years ago
女朋友多年前跟我说的那样，
she's going I think there's going to be
我觉得人类社会将会
a split yeah and I kind of like you know
分裂。是啊，我当时有点
whatever but now I'm like I can see why
无所谓，但现在我明白了，随着
as things get more extreme you go you
事态发展到极端，你会想，你知道吗，我要
know what I'm going to make a decision
做出决定了。
here and especially when I saw the
尤其是当我看到
neuralink that Elon musk's working on
埃隆·马斯克正在研发的Neuralink，它
that allows you to control computers
能让你用
with your brain I sat on and the
大脑控制电脑时，我坐在那里，想象着
computer to control your brain also it
电脑控制你的大脑，
both it go both you're right actually
两者兼而有之。你说得对，我之前没想过
didn't think about that but I just
这一点，但我只是
imagined um and this is a question for
想象了一下。嗯，这个问题问
everyone listening if there's you and me
所有在听的人：假设有你和我，
and I have the chip in my brain that now
我的大脑里植入了现在
humans have in their brain that they're
人类大脑里
using to control computers with I am a
用来控制电脑的芯片，那我
different species to you because I can
跟你就不是同一个物种了，因为我可以
control the I can control my car
控制……我可以控制
downstairs I can control the lights in
楼下的车，我可以控制房间里的灯，
this room I can I can ask my brain
我可以问我的大脑
questions and get the answers my IQ
问题并得到答案，我的智商
becomes 5,000 yours is still 150 or 200
会变成5000，而你的智商还是150。  200，
yours is probably
你的可能得
250 but I'm a different species to I
250，但我跟你不一样，我比你
have such a huge competitive advantage
拥有巨大的竞争优势，
over you that if you don't get the chip
如果你拿不到芯片，
then you you're screwed that's
你就完蛋了。这就是物种
speciation yeah again on a small scale
形成。是的，我们以前在小范围内也
we saw it before in history there were
见过这种情况。历史上有些
the people who adopted the written
人接受了
document and the people who rejected it
文字，有些人拒绝了，对吧？
right and they are not with us anymore
他们现在已经不在了。
because the people who adopted the
因为接受
written document they built these
文字的人建立了
kingdoms and Empires and they conquered
王国和帝国，征服了
else um and we are in danger of the same
其他所有人。我们现在也面临着同样的危险，
thing happening and this is not a good
这不是
thing because it's not like life was
好事，因为
better for the people with the documents
拥有文字的人生活并没有更好。在
in many cases life was better for the
很多情况下，以前的狩猎采集者生活得更好。
before so what's the solution if I had
那么，解决方案是什么？
to you know having read your book
读过你的书《
brilliant book Nexus a brief history of
Nexus》（一本精彩的书，讲述了
information networks from the Stone Age
从石器时代到人工智能的信息网络简史）之后，我该如何
solution how do we how do we stop the
解决这个问题？我们该如何阻止
alignment problems us all becoming paper
联盟问题，阻止我们所有人变成
clips the social chaos the
回形针，阻止社会混乱、
misinformation the the Silicon curtain
错误信息和
as you talk about in the book how do we
你在书中提到的“硅幕”？我们该如何
stop these things destroying our world
阻止这些东西摧毁我们的世界？
is there is there hope are you
还有希望吗？你
optimistic the key is is is is
乐观吗？ 关键在于
cooperation is connection between humans
合作，在于人与人之间的联系。我的
I mean the humans are still more
意思是，人类仍然
powerful than the AIS the problem is
比人工智能更强大。问题在于
that we are divided against each other
我们彼此分裂，
and the algorithms unintentionally are
而算法无意中
increasing the Divide again this is the
加剧了这种分裂。
oldest rule of every Empire is divid and
分而治之是所有帝国最古老的法则，罗马
of of the British Empire if you want
帝国和英国都是如此。如果你
want to rule a place you divide the
想统治一个地方，你就挑拨
people of that place against one another
那里的人民互相敌对，
and then it's easy to manipulate and
这样就很容易操纵和
control them uh this is now happening to
控制他们。现在，
the entire human species with AI that
人工智能正在对整个人类造成同样的影响。就像
Iron Curtain in the Cold War now we have
冷战时期的铁幕一样，现在我们有了
the Silicon curtain dividing not just
硅幕，它不仅分隔了
China from the US but also Democrats
中国和美国，还分隔了民主党和
from Republicans also one person from
共和党，分隔了人与人，也分隔了
another person and all of us from the
我们所有人与
AIS which increasingly make the
人工智能。人工智能越来越多地左右着这
decisions about all that uh we still
一切的决策。我们仍然
have the power for I don't know 5 years
有能力在未来5年、
10 years 20 years to to to make sure it
10年、20年内确保它
doesn't go in dystopian Direction but
不会走向反乌托邦的方向，但
for that we need to cooperate are you
为此我们需要合作。你
optimistic um I try to be a realist I
乐观吗？我尽量保持现实主义。我的
mean the last few I mean I just came
意思是，在过去的几年里…… 我刚从
from Israel and I saw a country
以色列回来，亲眼目睹一个国家
destroying itself for no good reason
毫无理由地自我毁灭。这个
whatsoever I it's a country that just
国家就像
pressed the self-destruct button and for
按下了自毁按钮，而且
no good reason and it can happen on a
没有任何正当理由。这种情况可能会在
global scale what do you mean I press
全球范围内发生。你说我按下
the self-destruct button it's not just
自毁按钮是什么意思？这不仅仅是
the war between Israelis and
以色列人和巴勒斯坦人之间的战争，
Palestinians but Israel Society turning
而是以色列社会内部日益加剧的
Division and
分裂和
animosity and uh it's it's like a a a a
敌意。这就像一个充满
dark hole of uh uh of of anger and of
愤怒和
violence which is sucking more and more
暴力的黑洞，正在吞噬越来越多的
people in you know all over the world
人。你知道，全世界的人
you now feel the shock waves from this
现在都能感受到来自中东这个黑洞的冲击波。没有任何正当
there is no good reason there is no
理由，没有任何
objective reason if I'll say something
客观理由。如果我说说
about the Israeli Palestinian conflict
以巴冲突，那就是
there is no objective reason for it it's
没有任何客观理由。这不像
between the Mediterranean and the Jordan
地中海和约旦河之间没有足够的土地，
River that people have to fight for the
人们不得不为那点
little land there is or there is not
可怜的土地而战；也不像没有
enough food there is enough food for
足够的粮食，粮食足够
everyone to eat there is enough land to
所有人食用；也有足够的土地来
build houses and and hospitals and
建造房屋、医院和
schools for everyone why do people fight
学校。为什么人们要
because of different stories in their
因为各种各样的理由而战呢？ 他们的
minds they have these different
思想里充斥着各种
mythologies that God gave this whole
神话，比如上帝把这整个
place just to us you have no right to be
地方都赐给了我们，而你没有权利待在
here and they fight over
这里。他们为此争斗不休。
that and uh um this is a local or
嗯，这虽然是一场局部或
Regional tragedy it can happen on a
区域性的悲剧，但它也可能在
global scale again if if something
全球范围内重演。如果
ultimately destroys us it will be our
最终有什么能毁灭我们，那将是我们
own delusions not the AIS the AI they
自身的妄想，而不是人工智能。人工智能之所以能
get their opening because of our
找到机会，是因为我们的
weaknesses because of our
弱点，因为我们的
delusions yal thank you so much for
妄想。非常感谢你
writing a book I think this book is one
写了这本书。我认为这本书是我读过的
of the most well-timed books um that
最应时之作之一，
I've ever come across because of
因为它反映了
right now and it really helped me to
当今世界正在发生的一切。它真的帮助我
understand that the problem isn't
理解，问题不
necessarily me versus you if you're on
在于你我之争，而在于
that we consume who's controlling those
我们所消费的信息网络。谁在控制这些
networks of information um somebody is
信息网络？有人在
manipulating us to be on different side
操纵我们，让我们站在不同的阵营，
not just to be on different sides but to
不仅如此，还要让我们
see each other as enemies and right now
视彼此为敌人。现在
that's a person but it might not be soon
这个人是个人，但也许很快就不是了，
it might not be a person no and
也许不再是个人了。
understanding that I think helps us
我认为理解这一点有助于我们找到问题的
focus on the root cause of of issues
根源。 有时候，问题的根源
that are sometimes hard to identify I I
很难确定。我
think the problem is my neighbor I think
认为问题出在我的邻居身上，我认为
it's that person with different color
是那个肤色不同的人。
skin but actually if look one level
但实际上，如果我
deeper it's the information networks and
深入思考，就会发现问题在于信息网络以及
what I'm being exposed to that are
我接触到的信息，它们在对
brainwashing me and creating those
我进行洗脑，制造各种
stories and as you talk about in your
故事。正如你在
previous book stories are ultimately
上一本书中提到的，故事最终
what are running the world and it's and
主宰着世界。这
wonderful book at a wonderful time that
本书很棒，《Nexus》在这样一个美好的时刻出版，它
helps us to access um this knowledge of
帮助我们了解
the power of information and and how it
信息的力量，以及它如何
impacts democracy and relationships and
影响民主、人际关系、
society and business and everything in
社会、商业以及介于两者之间的一切。
between um in a way that I hope
我希望这本书
will lead to action and I think that is
能引导我们采取行动，我认为这是值得
something to be optimistic about yeah
乐观的。是的，
ultimately I
最终我
think most humans are are good they're
认为大多数人都是善良的，他们是
good people yeah when you give people
好人。当你给人们提供
bad information they made bad decisions
错误信息时，他们会做出错误的决定。
the problem is not with the humans it's
问题不在于人，而在于
information amen you we have a closing
信息。阿门。我们
tradition on this podcast where the last
这个播客有个结束语，上一位
guest leaves the question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，
guest not knowing who they're going to
而不知道下一位嘉宾是谁。
be leaving it for oh okay and the
好的，
question left for you
留给你的问题
is what does it mean to be
是：强大意味着什么？
um to to accept reality as it
接受现实，直面
is uh to deal with reality without
现实，而不是
trying to hide it disappear it uh put a
试图掩盖、消除或
veil over
粉饰它。很
it so interesting
有意思，
I think you're
我觉得你说得对。当然，这
right I think you're right certainly not
肯定不是
the answer I would have given but you
我会给出的答案。但你
know you come what would you
知道，你会怎么
say
说呢？
um oh what would I
嗯，我会怎么
say I guess I probably would have spoken
说呢？我想我可能会谈到在
to like perseverance in the face of a
面对
lot of different difficulties and one of
各种困难时坚持不懈，其中之一
those is is information but it's just
就是获取信息。但关键在于，要
that that idea of like persevering
坚持不懈地
towards whatever your subjective goal is
朝着你的主观目标前进，即使面对
in the face of and in spite of a variety
各种各样的
of different difficulties maybe that
困难，这种
strength um so that could be raising a
力量……嗯，这可以是养育
kid or it could be going to the gym or
孩子，也可以是去健身房
whatever but I like your definition as
等等。但我很喜欢你的定义，
well because I think it's much more um
因为我认为
important in the times we find ourselves
在当今时代，这更加重要。说
in and there's honestly as a podcaster
实话，作为一名播客，
you sometimes feel like you're caught
你有时会觉得自己被夹
right in the middle of it because I
在中间，因为我
think everyone's trying to figure out if
觉得每个人都在试图弄清楚
I'm like on the right wing on the left
我是右翼还是
wing if I believe this if I endorse
左翼，我是否相信这个，我是否支持我邀请的
every guest that I sit with and you
每一位嘉宾。你
almost have to try and remain impartial
几乎…… 努力保持中立，
H but it's very very
但是这很难
uh difficult to for people to understand
让人理解，
that because they want you to fit
因为他们希望你符合某种标准，
somewhere and they want because that's
他们认为那是
weakness I mean you have a lot of people
软弱的表现。我的意思是，很多人
who who claim to be very strong who
自称很强大，他们把
admire strength as as as a value yeah
力量当作一种价值观，
but they can't deal with parts of
但他们无法接受
reality that don't fit into their
现实中那些不符合他们
worldview or their desire yeah and they
世界观或愿望的部分。他们
think that strength is I have the
认为力量就是我有
strength to just make these parts of
能力让这些
reality disappear yeah and no this is
现实部分消失，但这恰恰是
weakness and again sorry for going back
软弱的表现。抱歉我又回到这个话题了，
to that but but this is also the war
但这其实也是战争的本质。战争就是试图抹杀
a part of reality that you don't like in
你不喜欢的现实，在
this case an entire people I don't like
这个例子里，就是试图抹杀整个民族。我不喜欢
these people I don't think they should
这些人，我认为他们不应该
be in reality so I try to make them
存在于现实中，所以我试图让他们
disappear and people say oh he's a very
消失。人们会说，哦，他是个非常
strong leader is not he's a very weak
强大的领导者，不，他是个非常软弱的
leader that a strong leader would be
领导者。一个强大的领导者…… 如果阿德尔
able to acknowledge no these people
能够承认这些人确实
exist they are part of reality let's now
存在，他们是现实的一部分，那么现在让我们来
find out how do we live with
看看我们该如何与他们共存。
Mustafa Solomon but also Steven fry and
阿门。你的著作《Nexus：从石器时代到人工智能的信息网络简史》是所有收听本播客并对这些主题感兴趣的人的必读之作。这本书得到了我最喜欢的两位人物——穆斯塔法·所罗门、史蒂芬·弗莱以及
Rory stwart who's a great person as well
罗里·斯图尔特的推荐，罗里·斯图尔特也是一位非常棒的人。这本书之所以受到
as well um and it's endorsed for a very
推荐，是
good reason because it's a completely
因为它完全
mind expanding book written from someone
拓展了人们的思维，出自一位只
who only writes exceptional culture
创作具有文化
shifting books so I'm going to link it
变革意义的杰出著作的作家之手。我会在
below and I highly recommend anybody
下面附上链接，我强烈建议所有
that's listened to this conversation and
收听过本次对话并对
that's interested in this subject matter
这个主题感兴趣的人现在
to go and get this book right now it's
就去购买这本书。它现在可以
available right now for pre-order and
预购，
then it's shipping in five days from now
五天后正式发售，
when it releases so be the first to read
所以快来抢先阅读吧！
it um and hopefully be the first to
希望你也能成为第一批
understand and action some of the things
理解并实践
that you learn in this book y thank you
书中所学知识的人。
so much for your time thank
非常感谢你抽出时间。
you isn't this cool every single
谢谢。 这很酷吧？
conversation I have here on the Diary of
我在《CEO日记》节目中的每一期节目
a CEO at the very end of it you'll know
最后都会
I asked the guest to leave a question in
请嘉宾留下一个问题，
the Diary of a CEO and what we've done
而我们把
is we've turned every single question
所有问题都做成了
conversation cards that you can play at
对话卡片，你可以在
home so you've got every guest we've
家里玩。卡片背面印着所有嘉宾的问题，
of it if you scan that QR code you get
扫描二维码就能
to watch the person who answered that
看到回答
question we're finally revealing all of
问题的人。现在，我们终于要公布所有
the questions and the people that
问题和回答者了！全新
version 2 updated conversation cards are
第二版对话卡片现已
out right now at Theon conversation
在Theon
cards.com they've sold out twice
conversationcards.com网站发售，而且已经两次
instantaneously so if you are interested
瞬间售罄。所以，如果你想
in getting hold of some limited edition
入手一些限量版
conversation cards I really really
对话卡片，我强烈
recommend acting quickly oh
建议你抓紧时间！哦，
[Music]
[音乐]